{
  "description": "Endless 四字熟語 for your pleasure",
  "deck": [
  { "question": "一世一代", "answers": [ "いっせいちだい" ], "comment": "once in a lifetime; the first and last occurrence (event, experience) of one's lifetime" },
  { "question": "一世一元", "answers": [ "いっせいいちげん" ], "comment": "the practice of assigning one era name to one emperor" },
  { "question": "一世之雄", "answers": [ "いっせいのゆう" ] },
  { "question": "一人当千", "answers": [ "いちにんとうせん" ], "comment": "being a match for a thousand" },
  { "question": "一件落着", "answers": [ "いっけんらくちゃく" ], "comment": "an issue being settled; a case being closed" },
  { "question": "一億一心", "answers": [ "いちおくいっしん" ] },
  { "question": "一六勝負", "answers": [ "いちろくしょうぶ" ], "comment": "gambling; speculation" },
  { "question": "一刀両断", "answers": [ "いっとうりょうだん" ], "comment": "cutting in two with a single stroke; taking decisive (drastic) measure; cutting the (Gordian) knot" },
  { "question": "一分一厘", "answers": [ "いちぶいちりん" ], "comment": "(not even) a bit of; (not even) a hint of; (not) an iota of" },
  { "question": "一切即一", "answers": [ "いっさいそくいち" ] },
  { "question": "一切合切", "answers": [ "いっさいがっさい" ], "comment": "any and every thing; altogether; lock, stock, and barrel; the whole shooting match; the whole kit and caboodle; without reserve" },
  { "question": "一切皆成", "answers": [ "いっさいかいじょう" ] },
  { "question": "一切衆生", "answers": [ "いっさいしゅじょう" ], "comment": "all living creatures" },
  { "question": "一別以来", "answers": [ "いちべついらい" ], "comment": "since our last meeting; since we parted" },
  { "question": "一利一害", "answers": [ "いちりいちがい" ], "comment": "advantages and disadvantages; gain some, lose some" },
  { "question": "一刻千秋", "answers": [ "いっこくせんしゅう" ] },
  { "question": "一刻千金", "answers": [ "いっこくせんきん" ], "comment": "every moment is precious; time is money; precious time" },
  { "question": "一味徒党", "answers": [ "いちみととう" ], "comment": "whole party to a plot; whole gang; fellow conspirators" },
  { "question": "一問一答", "answers": [ "いちもんいっとう" ], "comment": "answering question by question" },
  { "question": "一喜一憂", "answers": [ "いっきいちゆう" ], "comment": "now rejoicing, now worrying; swinging from joy to sorrow; glad and sad by turns; alternating hope and fear; unable to put one's mind at ease" },
  { "question": "一国一城", "answers": [ "いっこくいちじょう" ], "comment": "(possession of) one feudal domain and one castle; being independent (acting without compromise or assistance)\nestablishing only one castle in each feudal domain (edict issued by the shogunate in 1615)" },
  { "question": "一大決心", "answers": [ "いちだいけっしん" ], "comment": "momentous (crucial) decision" },
  { "question": "一天万乗", "answers": [ "いってんばんじょう" ], "comment": "the whole realm" },
  { "question": "一夫一婦", "answers": [ "いっぷいっぷ" ], "comment": "monogamy" },
  { "question": "一夫多妻", "answers": [ "いっぷたさい" ], "comment": "polygamy; polygyny" },
  { "question": "一子相伝", "answers": [ "いっしそうでん" ], "comment": "transmission of the secrets of an art, craft, trade or learning from father to only one child" },
  { "question": "一字一句", "answers": [ "いちじいっく" ], "comment": "word for word; verbatim; a single word and a single phrase" },
  { "question": "一家団欒", "answers": [ "いっかだんらん" ], "comment": "happy family get-together" },
  { "question": "一家相伝", "answers": [ "いっかそうでん" ] },
  { "question": "一家眷族", "answers": [ "いっかけんぞく" ] },
  { "question": "一宿一飯", "answers": [ "いっしゅくいっぱん" ], "comment": "(being beholden to someone for a favor of) a night's lodging and a meal" },
  { "question": "一心不乱", "answers": [ "いっしんふらん" ], "comment": "wholeheartedly; with heart and soul; intently; with undivided attention; with intense concentration; single-mindedly" },
  { "question": "一心同体", "answers": [ "いっしんどうたい" ], "comment": "being one in body and soul; of one flesh; two hearts beating as one" },
  { "question": "一念万年", "answers": [ "いちねんばんねん" ] },
  { "question": "一念発起", "answers": [ "いちねんほっき" ], "comment": "being resolved to (do something); having a wholehearted intention" },
  { "question": "一意専心", "answers": [ "いちいせんしん" ], "comment": "single-mindedly; wholeheartedly; with one's heart and soul" },
  { "question": "一所不住", "answers": [ "いっしょふじゅう" ], "comment": "vagrant\ntransient lifestyle" },
  { "question": "一所懸命", "answers": [ "いっしょけんめい" ], "comment": "very hard; with utmost effort; with all one's might; desperately; frantically; for dear life; all-out effort; sticking at living in and defending one place\nsticking at living in one place" },
  { "question": "一挙一動", "answers": [ "いっきょいちどう" ], "comment": "one's every action; every single move" },
  { "question": "一挙両得", "answers": [ "いっきょりょうとく" ], "comment": "killing two birds with one stone; serving two ends" },
  { "question": "一攫千金", "answers": [ "いっかくせんきん" ], "comment": "getting rich quick; making a killing; making a fortune at a single stroke" },
  { "question": "一新紀元", "answers": [ "いちしんきげん" ], "comment": "new era; new age" },
  { "question": "一方通行", "answers": [ "いっぽうつうこう" ], "comment": "one-way traffic" },
  { "question": "一族郎党", "answers": [ "いちぞくろうとう" ], "comment": "one's family and followers; one's whole clan" },
  { "question": "一日千秋", "answers": [ "いちじつせんしゅう" ], "comment": "(waiting) impatiently; (spending) many a weary day; each moment seeming like an eternity" },
  { "question": "一旦緩急", "answers": [ "いったんかんきゅう" ], "comment": "(when) danger threatens; should an emergency occur" },
  { "question": "一時流行", "answers": [ "いちじりゅうこう" ] },
  { "question": "一望千里", "answers": [ "いちぼうせんり" ], "comment": "sweeping view of the eye; boundless expanse" },
  { "question": "一朝一夕", "answers": [ "いっちょういっせき" ], "comment": "in a day; in a brief space of time" },
  { "question": "一期一会", "answers": [ "いちごいちえ" ], "comment": "once-in-a-lifetime encounter (hence should be cherished as such)" },
  { "question": "一木一草", "answers": [ "いちぼくいっそう" ], "comment": "a single tree or blade of grass; every stick and stone (of a place)" },
  { "question": "一本調子", "answers": [ "いっぽんぢょうし" ], "comment": "monotone" },
  { "question": "一枚看板", "answers": [ "いちまいかんばん" ], "comment": "leading player; prima donna; box-office star\nbest item one has (to show); one's sole Sunday best; one's single area of expertise" },
  { "question": "一栄一落", "answers": [ "いちえいいちらく" ] },
  { "question": "一死報国", "answers": [ "いっしほうこく" ], "comment": "dying for one's country" },
  { "question": "一殺多生", "answers": [ "いっせつたしょう" ], "comment": "It is justifiable to kill one (harmful) person to save the lives of many" },
  { "question": "一気呵成", "answers": [ "いっきかせい" ], "comment": "finishing writing, work, etc. at a stroke (stretch); knocking something off without a break" },
  { "question": "一汁一菜", "answers": [ "いちじゅういっさい" ], "comment": "one-plate meal; simple meal; austerity diet" },
  { "question": "一波万波", "answers": [ "いっぱばんぱ" ] },
  { "question": "一瀉千里", "answers": [ "いっしゃせんり" ], "comment": "one swift effort; rush through one's work; fast-talking, writing, etc." },
  { "question": "一点一画", "answers": [ "いってんいっかく" ], "comment": "the dots of i's and the crosses of t's; (not neglecting) the slightest details" },
  { "question": "一生不犯", "answers": [ "いっしょうふぼん" ], "comment": "(strict) observance of the Buddhist precept of lifelong celibacy" },
  { "question": "一生懸命", "answers": [ "いっしょうけんめい" ], "comment": "very hard; with utmost effort; with all one's might; for dear life" },
  { "question": "一病息災", "answers": [ "いちびょうそくさい" ], "comment": "one who experiences a chronic ailment takes better care of his health and lives longer" },
  { "question": "一発必中", "answers": [ "いっぱつひっちゅう" ], "comment": "success on the first try (attempt)" },
  { "question": "一目瞭然", "answers": [ "いちもくりょうぜん" ], "comment": "apparent; obvious; very clear" },
  { "question": "一知半解", "answers": [ "いっちはんかい" ], "comment": "superficial knowledge; half knowledge" },
  { "question": "一石二鳥", "answers": [ "いっせきにちょう" ], "comment": "killing two birds with one stone" },
  { "question": "一竿風月", "answers": [ "いっかんのふうげつ" ] },
  { "question": "一筆啓上", "answers": [ "いっぴつけいじょう" ], "comment": "Just a short note to tell you ...; This will just be a short note" },
  { "question": "一結杳然", "answers": [ "いっけつようぜん" ] },
  { "question": "一網打尽", "answers": [ "いちもうだじん" ], "comment": "(a) big haul; roundup; wholesale arrest; catching the whole herd with one throw" },
  { "question": "一罰百戒", "answers": [ "いちばつひゃっかい" ], "comment": "punishing a crime to make an example for others" },
  { "question": "一致団結", "answers": [ "いっちだんけつ" ], "comment": "solidarity; banding together and working as one for a common cause" },
  { "question": "一草一木", "answers": [ "いっそういちぼく" ] },
  { "question": "一蓮托生", "answers": [ "いちれんたくしょう" ], "comment": "sharing one's lot with another" },
  { "question": "一行三昧", "answers": [ "いちぎょうざんまい" ] },
  { "question": "一視同仁", "answers": [ "いっしどうじん" ], "comment": "loving every human being with impartiality; universal brotherhood; universal benevolence" },
  { "question": "一触即発", "answers": [ "いっしょくそくはつ" ], "comment": "critical (touch and go) situation; explosive situation" },
  { "question": "一言一句", "answers": [ "いちごんいっく" ], "comment": "every single word and phrase; word by word" },
  { "question": "一言一行", "answers": [ "いちげんいっこう" ], "comment": "every word and act; just a word or an act" },
  { "question": "一言半句", "answers": [ "いちごんはんく" ], "comment": "a single word; (not even) a word; (not even) a syllable" },
  { "question": "一言居士", "answers": [ "いちげんこじ" ], "comment": "person who is ready to comment on every subject; ready critic" },
  { "question": "一語一句", "answers": [ "いちごいっく" ], "comment": "every single word and phrase; each and every word" },
  { "question": "一諾千金", "answers": [ "いちだくせんきん" ], "comment": "one's word is worth 1,000 pieces of gold; a promise should be kept at all cost" },
  { "question": "一路平安", "answers": [ "いちろへいあん" ], "comment": "(wishing someone) bon voyage" },
  { "question": "一進一退", "answers": [ "いっしんいったい" ], "comment": "now advancing and now retreating; ebb and flow; seesawing; taking alternately favorable and unfavorable turns" },
  { "question": "一部始終", "answers": [ "いちぶしじゅう" ], "comment": "full particulars; the whole story; from beginning to end" },
  { "question": "一銭一厘", "answers": [ "いっせんいちりん" ] },
  { "question": "一長一短", "answers": [ "いっちょういったん" ], "comment": "(something having its) merits and demerits; advantages and disadvantages; good points and shortcomings" },
  { "question": "一陽来復", "answers": [ "いちようらいふく" ], "comment": "return of spring; long-awaited, favorable turn of fortune (favourable)" },
  { "question": "一飯君恩", "answers": [ "いっぱんくんおん" ] },
  { "question": "一騎当千", "answers": [ "いっきとうせん" ], "comment": "being a match for a thousand; being a mighty warrior (combatant, player)" },
  { "question": "丁々発止", "answers": [ "ちょうちょうはっし" ], "comment": "(sound) of clashing swords; (arguing) as fiercely as clashing and blocking swords" },
  { "question": "七五三縄", "answers": [ "しめなわ" ], "comment": "rope used to cordon off consecrated areas or as a talisman against evil" },
  { "question": "七堂伽藍", "answers": [ "しちどうがらん" ], "comment": "complete seven-structured temple compound" },
  { "question": "七擒七縦", "answers": [ "しちきんしちしょう" ] },
  { "question": "七珍万宝", "answers": [ "しっちんまんぽう" ], "comment": "the seven treasures and many other precious things; all the treasures in the world" },
  { "question": "七生報国", "answers": [ "しちしょうほうこく" ], "comment": "unfailing devotion to one's country" },
  { "question": "七転八倒", "answers": [ "しちてんばっとう" ], "comment": "tossing oneself about in great pain; writhing in agony" },
  { "question": "七転八起", "answers": [ "しちてんはっき" ], "comment": "the vicissitudes of life; ups and downs in life; always rising after a fall or repeated failures" },
  { "question": "七難八苦", "answers": [ "しちなんはっく" ], "comment": "the Seven Misfortunes and Eight Pains\na series of disasters" },
  { "question": "万世一系", "answers": [ "ばんせいいっけい" ], "comment": "unbroken imperial line" },
  { "question": "万世不易", "answers": [ "ばんせいふえき" ], "comment": "eternity; perpetuity" },
  { "question": "万代不易", "answers": [ "ばんだいふえき" ], "comment": "eternity; perpetuity" },
  { "question": "万古不易", "answers": [ "ばんこふえき" ], "comment": "eternally unchanging" },
  { "question": "万古不磨", "answers": [ "ばんこふま" ] },
  { "question": "万国共通", "answers": [ "ばんこくきょうつう" ], "comment": "worldwide; common to the whole world; universal" },
  { "question": "万夫不当", "answers": [ "ばんぷふとう" ], "comment": "being a match for thousands; being a mighty warrior (combatant)" },
  { "question": "万物流転", "answers": [ "ばんぶつるてん" ], "comment": "all things are in a state of flux; everything is constantly changing" },
  { "question": "三々五々", "answers": [ "さんさんごご" ], "comment": "in groups of twos and threes; in small groups" },
  { "question": "三位一体", "answers": [ "さんみいったい" ], "comment": "the Trinity" },
  { "question": "三十六計", "answers": [ "さんじゅうろっけい" ], "comment": "the 36 (ancient Chinese military) strategies (of which the last resort was said to be beating a retreat)" },
  { "question": "三千世界", "answers": [ "さんぜんせかい" ], "comment": "the whole world; the universe" },
  { "question": "三千寵愛", "answers": [ "さんぜんのちょうあい" ] },
  { "question": "三寒四温", "answers": [ "さんかんしおん" ], "comment": "alternation of three cold and four warm days" },
  { "question": "三拝九拝", "answers": [ "さんぱいきゅうはい" ], "comment": "kowtowing; bowing repeatedly" },
  { "question": "三日坊主", "answers": [ "みっかぼうず" ], "comment": "person who cannot stick to anything; unsteady worker; monk for three days" },
  { "question": "三日天下", "answers": [ "みっかてんか" ], "comment": "short-lived rule; being in power only for a brief period; brief championship" },
  { "question": "三段論法", "answers": [ "さんだんろんぽう" ], "comment": "syllogism" },
  { "question": "三百代言", "answers": [ "さんびゃくだいげん" ], "comment": "pettifogging lawyer; unscrupulous or unethical lawyer; shyster\ncasuist; sophist" },
  { "question": "三者三様", "answers": [ "さんしゃさんよう" ], "comment": "each of the three being different from the other two; each of the three having his (her) own way" },
  { "question": "三者鼎立", "answers": [ "さんしゃていりつ" ], "comment": "three parties (forces) opposing one another; three-cornered contest" },
  { "question": "三蔵法師", "answers": [ "さんぞうほうし" ] },
  { "question": "三角関係", "answers": [ "さんかくかんけい" ], "comment": "love triangle; eternal triangle" },
  { "question": "三面六臂", "answers": [ "さんめんろっぴ" ], "comment": "rush of business; versatility; man who can do the work of many" },
  { "question": "上下一心", "answers": [ "しょうかいっしん" ] },
  { "question": "上意下達", "answers": [ "じょういかたつ" ], "comment": "conveying the will of the governing to the governed" },
  { "question": "上昇気流", "answers": [ "じょうしょうきりゅう" ], "comment": "ascending air current; updraft\nupward trend; rise in popularity, influence, etc." },
  { "question": "不倶戴天", "answers": [ "ふぐたいてん" ], "comment": "cannot allow (oneself) to live (with someone) under the canopy of heaven; cannot allow (the sworn enemy) to live in this world; irreconcilable (enemy)" },
  { "question": "不偏不党", "answers": [ "ふへんふとう" ], "comment": "impartiality; neutrality; independence" },
  { "question": "不労所得", "answers": [ "ふろうしょとく" ], "comment": "unearned income" },
  { "question": "不協和音", "answers": [ "ふきょうわおん" ], "comment": "discord; dissonance" },
  { "question": "不即不離", "answers": [ "ふそくふり" ], "comment": "neutral; noncommittal" },
  { "question": "不可思議", "answers": [ "ふかしぎ" ], "comment": "mystery; something inexplicable; wonder; miracle\nunfathomable (of a Buddha's abilities)\n10^64 (or 10^80)" },
  { "question": "不可抗力", "answers": [ "ふかこうりょく" ], "comment": "act of God; irresistible force; inevitability\nforce majeure; vis major" },
  { "question": "不同不二", "answers": [ "ふどうふじ" ] },
  { "question": "不在証明", "answers": [ "ふざいしょうめい" ], "comment": "alibi" },
  { "question": "不埒千万", "answers": [ "ふらちせんばん" ], "comment": "very insolent; extremely audacious; reprehensible" },
  { "question": "不壊金剛", "answers": [ "ふえこんごう" ] },
  { "question": "不屈不撓", "answers": [ "ふくつふとう" ], "comment": "indefatigability; indomitableness; with unremitting tenacity" },
  { "question": "不平不満", "answers": [ "ふへいふまん" ], "comment": "discontent and grumbling" },
  { "question": "不得要領", "answers": [ "ふとくようりょう" ], "comment": "vague; ambiguous; noncommittal; off-point" },
  { "question": "不惜身命", "answers": [ "ふしゃくしんみょう" ], "comment": "not sparing one's life for a worthy cause" },
  { "question": "不承不承", "answers": [ "ふしょうぶしょう" ], "comment": "reluctantly; grudgingly; unwillingly" },
  { "question": "不撓不屈", "answers": [ "ふとうふくつ" ], "comment": "inflexibility; tenacity; indomitableness" },
  { "question": "不眠不休", "answers": [ "ふみんふきゅう" ], "comment": "without sleep or rest; day and night" },
  { "question": "不立文字", "answers": [ "ふりゅうもんじ" ], "comment": "Buddhist revelation through intuitive discernment; Spiritual awakening cannot be experienced with words and letters; Spiritual enlightenment can be attained only by means of communion of mind with mind (Zen Buddhism)" },
  { "question": "不羈奔放", "answers": [ "ふきほんぽう" ], "comment": "free-spirited and uninhibited" },
  { "question": "不老不死", "answers": [ "ふろうふし" ], "comment": "perpetual youth and longevity; immortality" },
  { "question": "不老長寿", "answers": [ "ふろうちょうじゅ" ], "comment": "perpetual youth and longevity" },
  { "question": "不老長生", "answers": [ "ふろうちょうせい" ] },
  { "question": "不要不急", "answers": [ "ふようふきゅう" ], "comment": "nonessential and nonurgent" },
  { "question": "不言不語", "answers": [ "ふげんふご" ], "comment": "silence" },
  { "question": "不言実行", "answers": [ "ふげんじっこう" ], "comment": "action before words; work before talk" },
  { "question": "世代交代", "answers": [ "せだいこうたい" ], "comment": "alternation of generations" },
  { "question": "世態人情", "answers": [ "せたいにんじょう" ], "comment": "(contemporary) customs and behavior; the picture of people's life in the contemporary world" },
  { "question": "世道人心", "answers": [ "せどうじんしん" ], "comment": "(public) morals and sentiments" },
  { "question": "中肉中背", "answers": [ "ちゅうにくちゅうぜい" ], "comment": "medium build" },
  { "question": "中途半端", "answers": [ "ちゅうとはんぱ" ], "comment": "halfway; half measures; unfinished; incomplete; by halves; half-baked; half-cocked" },
  { "question": "主客転倒", "answers": [ "しゅかくてんとう" ], "comment": "reversing the order of (relative) importance (of); putting the cart before the horse; the tables being turned; mistaking the insignificant for the essential; mistaking the means for the end" },
  { "question": "主権在民", "answers": [ "しゅけんざいみん" ], "comment": "the sovereignty of the people" },
  { "question": "主義主張", "answers": [ "しゅぎしゅちょう" ], "comment": "one's principles and position" },
  { "question": "九分九厘", "answers": [ "くぶくりん" ], "comment": "ten to one; nine cases out of ten" },
  { "question": "九十九折", "answers": [ "つづらおり" ], "comment": "winding; meandering; sinuous; zigzag" },
  { "question": "九寸五分", "answers": [ "くすんごぶ" ], "comment": "dagger" },
  { "question": "九年面壁", "answers": [ "くねんめんぺき" ] },
  { "question": "九死一生", "answers": [ "きゅうしいっしょう" ], "comment": "narrow escape from the jaw of death" },
  { "question": "乱暴狼藉", "answers": [ "らんぼうろうぜき" ], "comment": "running amok (amuck); committing an outrage; rampageous behavior" },
  { "question": "乱臣賊子", "answers": [ "らんしんぞくし" ], "comment": "rebels against one's lord and one's parents; rebellious (treacherous) subject; traitor" },
  { "question": "乱離骨灰", "answers": [ "らりこっぱい" ], "comment": "being scattered in all directions; being broken up and dispersed" },
  { "question": "乳母日傘", "answers": [ "おんばひがさ" ], "comment": "(bringing up a child) with greatest care pampering (him, her) with material comforts of a rich family; (being brought up) in a hothouse atmosphere" },
  { "question": "乾坤一擲", "answers": [ "けんこんいってき" ], "comment": "stake all (on something); play for all or nothing; throwing all into a task" },
  { "question": "乾燥無味", "answers": [ "かんそうむみ" ], "comment": "dryness; dullness" },
  { "question": "事大主義", "answers": [ "じだいしゅぎ" ], "comment": "worship of the powerful" },
  { "question": "事実無根", "answers": [ "じじつむこん" ], "comment": "groundless; entirely contrary to fact" },
  { "question": "事後承諾", "answers": [ "じごしょうだく" ], "comment": "ex-post-facto approval" },
  { "question": "事理明白", "answers": [ "じりめいはく" ], "comment": "facts being beyond dispute; logic being indisputable" },
  { "question": "二人三脚", "answers": [ "ににんさんきゃく" ], "comment": "three-legged race\ncooperation with singleness of purpose (e.g. between companies); operating in tandem" },
  { "question": "二六時中", "answers": [ "にろくじちゅう" ], "comment": "night and day; all the time" },
  { "question": "二律背反", "answers": [ "にりつはいはん" ], "comment": "antinomy; self-contradiction\neither-or situation; choice between mutually exclusive alternatives" },
  { "question": "二束三文", "answers": [ "にそくさんもん" ], "comment": "dirt cheap; very cheap" },
  { "question": "二枚看板", "answers": [ "にまいかんばん" ], "comment": "the two leading actors (in a play); the two star players; the two distinctive features; the two main items (attractions)" },
  { "question": "二河白道", "answers": [ "にがびゃくどう" ], "comment": "metaphor in which the road to paradise is likened to a white road between two rivers, one of water (wrath) and one of fire (greed)" },
  { "question": "二者択一", "answers": [ "にしゃたくいつ" ], "comment": "two alternatives; selecting an option (from two alternatives)" },
  { "question": "二者選一", "answers": [ "にしゃせんいつ" ], "comment": "two alternatives; selecting an option (from two alternatives)" },
  { "question": "二股膏薬", "answers": [ "ふたまたこうやく" ], "comment": "double-dealer; timeserver; moving back and forth between two sides in a conflict" },
  { "question": "二転三転", "answers": [ "にてんさんてん" ], "comment": "change again and again; seesaw back and forth; being in a state of flux; backtracking repeatedly" },
  { "question": "五体投地", "answers": [ "ごたいとうち" ], "comment": "prostration; placing knees, hands and forehead on the ground to show utmost respect" },
  { "question": "五分五分", "answers": [ "ごぶごぶ" ], "comment": "as likely as not; 50-50; even match; tie" },
  { "question": "五穀豊穣", "answers": [ "ごこくほうじょう" ], "comment": "huge harvest (of the five grains); bumper crop; abundant crop" },
  { "question": "五臓六腑", "answers": [ "ごぞうろっぷ" ], "comment": "the internal organs" },
  { "question": "五蘊皆空", "answers": [ "ごうんかいくう" ] },
  { "question": "五蘊盛苦", "answers": [ "ごうんじょうく" ] },
  { "question": "五里霧中", "answers": [ "ごりむちゅう" ], "comment": "totally at a loss; lose one's bearings; in a maze; in a fog; all at sea; up in the air; mystified; bewildered" },
  { "question": "亭主関白", "answers": [ "ていしゅかんぱく" ], "comment": "husband who rules the roost; domineering husband\nthe hectoring of the husband" },
  { "question": "人三化七", "answers": [ "にんさんばけしち" ] },
  { "question": "人事不省", "answers": [ "じんじふせい" ], "comment": "unconsciousness" },
  { "question": "人事考課", "answers": [ "じんじこうか" ], "comment": "merit (ability, efficiency) rating; employee performance evaluation" },
  { "question": "人事葛藤", "answers": [ "じんじかっとう" ] },
  { "question": "人品骨柄", "answers": [ "じんぴんこつがら" ], "comment": "personal appearance and physique; person's appearance and physique giving a feeling of respectable character" },
  { "question": "人心一新", "answers": [ "じんしんいっしん" ], "comment": "complete change in public sentiment; leading the thought of the people to an entirely different channel" },
  { "question": "人心収攬", "answers": [ "じんしんしゅうらん" ], "comment": "winning the hearts of the people; capturing public sentiment" },
  { "question": "人情世態", "answers": [ "にんじょうせたい" ] },
  { "question": "人権蹂躙", "answers": [ "じんけんじゅうりん" ], "comment": "human rights violation; trampling on human rights" },
  { "question": "人海戦術", "answers": [ "じんかいせんじゅつ" ], "comment": "human-wave tactics" },
  { "question": "人生行路", "answers": [ "じんせいこうろ" ], "comment": "journey of life" },
  { "question": "人畜無害", "answers": [ "じんちくむがい" ], "comment": "harmless to humans and animals\nhaving no influence; unimportant; insignificant; harmless" },
  { "question": "人相風体", "answers": [ "にんそうふうてい" ], "comment": "someone's looks and personal appearance" },
  { "question": "人跡未踏", "answers": [ "じんせきみとう" ], "comment": "unexplored" },
  { "question": "人身御供", "answers": [ "ひとみごくう" ], "comment": "human sacrifice; victim" },
  { "question": "人身攻撃", "answers": [ "じんしんこうげき" ], "comment": "personal attack" },
  { "question": "人面獣心", "answers": [ "じんめんじゅうしん" ], "comment": "beast in human form" },
  { "question": "人面獣身", "answers": [ "じんめんじゅうしん" ] },
  { "question": "他人行儀", "answers": [ "たにんぎょうぎ" ], "comment": "standing on formality; in a reserved manner; treating a friend as a stranger; unduly distant; formal" },
  { "question": "他力本願", "answers": [ "たりきほんがん" ], "comment": "salvation by faith in Amitabha\nrelying upon others for attaining one's own objective" },
  { "question": "他言無用", "answers": [ "たごんむよう" ], "comment": "Not a word to anyone; Mum's the word" },
  { "question": "付和雷同", "answers": [ "ふわらいどう" ], "comment": "following blindly; following suit without reflection" },
  { "question": "以心伝心", "answers": [ "いしんでんしん" ], "comment": "telepathy; tacit understanding; communion of mind with mind; sympathy" },
  { "question": "会者定離", "answers": [ "えしゃじょうり" ], "comment": "those who meet must part (suggesting the transient nature of this life); we meet only to part" },
  { "question": "伯夷叔斉", "answers": [ "はくいしゅくせい" ] },
  { "question": "伸縮自在", "answers": [ "しんしゅくじざい" ], "comment": "elastic; flexible; telescoping; expandable; retractable; extensible" },
  { "question": "位階勲等", "answers": [ "いかいくんとう" ], "comment": "court rank and honors; court rank and honours" },
  { "question": "余裕綽綽", "answers": [ "よゆうしゃくしゃく" ], "comment": "calm and composed; broadminded; having enough and to spare" },
  { "question": "佳人薄命", "answers": [ "かじんはくめい" ], "comment": "beauties die young; beauty and luck seldom go together" },
  { "question": "侃侃諤諤", "answers": [ "かんかんがくがく" ], "comment": "outspoken; arguing (heatedly) what one believes in; insisting on something without restraint" },
  { "question": "依怙贔屓", "answers": [ "えこひいき" ], "comment": "favoritism; favouritism; partiality; prejudice; bias" },
  { "question": "俗談平語", "answers": [ "ぞくだんへいご" ] },
  { "question": "信賞必罰", "answers": [ "しんしょうひつばつ" ], "comment": "sure punishment or reward" },
  { "question": "俯仰天地", "answers": [ "ふぎょうてんち" ], "comment": "looking up and down, from heaven to earth (having nothing to be ashamed of); swearing by Heaven and Earth (having done nothing to be ashamed of)" },
  { "question": "偕老同穴", "answers": [ "かいろうどうけつ" ], "comment": "happy life partnership\nVenus's flower basket (species of sponge, Euplectella aspergillum); Venus flower basket" },
  { "question": "偶像崇拝", "answers": [ "ぐうぞうすうはい" ], "comment": "idolatry; idol worship" },
  { "question": "傀儡政権", "answers": [ "かいらいせいけん" ], "comment": "puppet government (regime)" },
  { "question": "傲岸不遜", "answers": [ "ごうがんふそん" ], "comment": "arrogance" },
  { "question": "傲岸無礼", "answers": [ "ごうがんぶれい" ], "comment": "arrogance" },
  { "question": "傲慢不遜", "answers": [ "ごうまんふそん" ], "comment": "haughty; arrogant; overbearing" },
  { "question": "傲慢無礼", "answers": [ "ごうまんぶれい" ], "comment": "(arrogance and) insolence" },
  { "question": "傾城傾国", "answers": [ "けいせいけいこく" ], "comment": "woman so glamorous as to bring ruin to a country (castle) as its king (lord) is captivated by her beauty; femme fatale" },
  { "question": "優勝劣敗", "answers": [ "ゆうしょうれっぱい" ], "comment": "survival of the fittest" },
  { "question": "優柔不断", "answers": [ "ゆうじゅうふだん" ], "comment": "shilly-shally; indecisiveness" },
  { "question": "元気溌剌", "answers": [ "げんきはつらつ" ], "comment": "full of energy; full of liveliness; full of pep" },
  { "question": "先制攻撃", "answers": [ "せんせいこうげき" ], "comment": "preemptive attack (strike)" },
  { "question": "先刻承知", "answers": [ "せんこくしょうち" ], "comment": "being already (well) aware" },
  { "question": "先手必勝", "answers": [ "せんてひっしょう" ], "comment": "victory goes to the one who makes the first move; being quick to take action leads to victory; the early bird gets the worm" },
  { "question": "先祖伝来", "answers": [ "せんぞでんらい" ], "comment": "inherited; family (heirloom); ancestral" },
  { "question": "光彩陸離", "answers": [ "こうさいりくり" ], "comment": "dazzling; brilliant" },
  { "question": "光明遍照", "answers": [ "こうみょうへんじょう" ] },
  { "question": "光輝燦然", "answers": [ "こうきさんぜん" ] },
  { "question": "免許皆伝", "answers": [ "めんきょかいでん" ], "comment": "possessing full mastery of an art (e.g. Judo); initiation into the secrets (e.g. of an art); full mastership" },
  { "question": "党利党略", "answers": [ "とうりとうりゃく" ], "comment": "party political interests; partisan politics" },
  { "question": "全力投球", "answers": [ "ぜんりょくとうきゅう" ], "comment": "using all of one's strength (to); giving (it) everything one has got; going full-out\nthrowing a ball as hard as one can" },
  { "question": "全知全能", "answers": [ "ぜんちぜんのう" ], "comment": "omniscience and omnipotence; all-knowing; almighty" },
  { "question": "全身全霊", "answers": [ "ぜんしんぜんれい" ], "comment": "complete devotion; body and soul; one's best" },
  { "question": "八大地獄", "answers": [ "はちだいじごく" ], "comment": "The Eight Greater Hells" },
  { "question": "八方美人", "answers": [ "はっぽうびじん" ], "comment": "everybody's friend; person who is affable to everybody\nflawlessly beautiful woman; flawless beauty" },
  { "question": "八紘一宇", "answers": [ "はっこういちう" ], "comment": "universal brotherhood; all eight corners of the world under one roof" },
  { "question": "八面六臂", "answers": [ "はちめんろっぴ" ], "comment": "competent in all fields; jack of all trades; very active in many fields; versatile; all-round; 8 faces and 6 arms" },
  { "question": "公平無私", "answers": [ "こうへいむし" ], "comment": "impartiality; fair play" },
  { "question": "公序良俗", "answers": [ "こうじょりょうぞく" ], "comment": "public order and morals; social standards; public policy" },
  { "question": "公明正大", "answers": [ "こうめいせいだい" ], "comment": "fairness; just and upright; aboveboard" },
  { "question": "公私混同", "answers": [ "こうしこんどう" ], "comment": "intermingling of public policy with private interest; mixing up official business with personal affairs" },
  { "question": "六根清浄", "answers": [ "ろっこんしょうじょう" ], "comment": "purification of the six roots of perception" },
  { "question": "六道輪廻", "answers": [ "ろくどうりんね" ], "comment": "endless circle of transmigration in the six posthumous worlds" },
  { "question": "六韜三略", "answers": [ "りくとうさんりゃく" ], "comment": "two books on the art of war in ancient China; the secrets (essence) of the art of war; secrets of successful life; precepts for living" },
  { "question": "共存共栄", "answers": [ "きょうぞんきょうえい" ], "comment": "co-existence and co-prosperity" },
  { "question": "兵馬倥偬", "answers": [ "へいばこうそう" ] },
  { "question": "具不退転", "answers": [ "ぐふたいてん" ] },
  { "question": "内憂外患", "answers": [ "ないゆうがいかん" ], "comment": "troubles both at home and abroad" },
  { "question": "内政干渉", "answers": [ "ないせいかんしょう" ], "comment": "interference in the domestic affairs of another country" },
  { "question": "円転滑脱", "answers": [ "えんてんかつだつ" ], "comment": "suave; tactful; smooth\nversatile; adaptable" },
  { "question": "再三再四", "answers": [ "さいさんさいし" ], "comment": "repeatedly" },
  { "question": "再起不能", "answers": [ "さいきふのう" ], "comment": "being beyond recovery; having no hope of recovery" },
  { "question": "冠婚葬祭", "answers": [ "かんこんそうさい" ], "comment": "important ceremonial occasions in family relationships" },
  { "question": "冠履顛倒", "answers": [ "かんりてんとう" ] },
  { "question": "冥頑不霊", "answers": [ "めいがんふれい" ] },
  { "question": "冷汗三斗", "answers": [ "れいかんさんと" ], "comment": "breaking into cold sweat when one is very embarrassed or scared" },
  { "question": "冷酷無情", "answers": [ "れいこくむじょう" ], "comment": "cruel and heartless; merciless; implacable" },
  { "question": "冷静沈着", "answers": [ "れいせいちんちゃく" ], "comment": "calm, cool, and collected; level and calm" },
  { "question": "出処進退", "answers": [ "しゅっしょしんたい" ], "comment": "advancing and retreating; appearance and disappearance; one's daily activities; one's course of action; one's attitude" },
  { "question": "出家遁世", "answers": [ "しゅっけとんせい" ], "comment": "monastic seclusion" },
  { "question": "出没自在", "answers": [ "しゅつぼつじざい" ], "comment": "appearing and disappearing at will; elusive; phantom-like" },
  { "question": "刀山剣樹", "answers": [ "とうざんけんじゅ" ] },
  { "question": "切歯扼腕", "answers": [ "せっしやくわん" ], "comment": "being enraged (indignant, impatient); gnashing the teeth and clenching the arms on the breast (in anger or regret)" },
  { "question": "切磋琢磨", "answers": [ "せっさたくま" ], "comment": "cultivating one's character by studying hard; diligent application\nmutual encouragement (to improve)" },
  { "question": "初志貫徹", "answers": [ "しょしかんてつ" ], "comment": "carrying out one's original intention" },
  { "question": "判官贔屓", "answers": [ "ほうがんびいき" ], "comment": "sympathy for a tragic hero; rooting for the underdog" },
  { "question": "利害得失", "answers": [ "りがいとくしつ" ], "comment": "advantages and disadvantages; pros and cons" },
  { "question": "利己主義", "answers": [ "りこしゅぎ" ], "comment": "egoism; selfishness" },
  { "question": "刹那主義", "answers": [ "せつなしゅぎ" ], "comment": "principle of living only for the moment" },
  { "question": "刻苦勉励", "answers": [ "こっくべんれい" ], "comment": "being arduous; working diligently enduring hardships" },
  { "question": "刻苦精励", "answers": [ "こっくせいれい" ], "comment": "being arduous; working diligently enduring hardships; making a strenuous effort" },
  { "question": "則天去私", "answers": [ "そくてんきょし" ], "comment": "selfless devotion to justice" },
  { "question": "前人未到", "answers": [ "ぜんじんみとう" ], "comment": "untrodden (region, field of study, etc.); unprecedented (discovery, achievement, etc.)" },
  { "question": "前代未聞", "answers": [ "ぜんだいみもん" ], "comment": "unheard-of; unprecedented; unparalleled in history (unparallelled); record-breaking" },
  { "question": "前後不覚", "answers": [ "ぜんごふかく" ], "comment": "unconsciousness; having no recollection of one's actions" },
  { "question": "前後矛盾", "answers": [ "ぜんごむじゅん" ], "comment": "self-contradiction; self-inconsistency" },
  { "question": "前途多難", "answers": [ "ぜんとたなん" ], "comment": "having many difficulties in store; grim prospects" },
  { "question": "前途有望", "answers": [ "ぜんとゆうぼう" ], "comment": "promising future" },
  { "question": "前途洋洋", "answers": [ "ぜんとようよう" ], "comment": "with a rosy future; offering promising prospects" },
  { "question": "前途遼遠", "answers": [ "ぜんとりょうえん" ], "comment": "goal; destination" },
  { "question": "剛健質朴", "answers": [ "ごうけんしつぼく" ] },
  { "question": "剛毅果断", "answers": [ "ごうきかだん" ], "comment": "dauntless and decisive; with fortitude and resolution" },
  { "question": "創意工夫", "answers": [ "そういくふう" ], "comment": "being imaginative and creative; creative originality" },
  { "question": "剽悍無比", "answers": [ "ひょうかんむひ" ], "comment": "as fierce and nimble as any; daring and agile without equal" },
  { "question": "力戦奮闘", "answers": [ "りきせんふんとう" ], "comment": "fighting with all one's might; fighting up against; making strenuous efforts" },
  { "question": "加持祈祷", "answers": [ "かじきとう" ], "comment": "incantation and prayer" },
  { "question": "効果覿面", "answers": [ "こうかてきめん" ], "comment": "bring an immediate result on; have an instant effect on" },
  { "question": "勇往邁進", "answers": [ "ゆうおうまいしん" ], "comment": "dash and go; pushing forward" },
  { "question": "勇猛果敢", "answers": [ "ゆうもうかかん" ], "comment": "daring and resolute; having dauntless courage" },
  { "question": "勇猛果断", "answers": [ "ゆうもうかだん" ] },
  { "question": "勇猛無比", "answers": [ "ゆうもうむひ" ], "comment": "most brave; as brave as any; unmatched for valor" },
  { "question": "勇猛精進", "answers": [ "ゆうもうしょうじん" ], "comment": "engage in ascetic practices with dauntless spirit" },
  { "question": "勝手気儘", "answers": [ "かってきまま" ], "comment": "self-willed; (doing or saying things) to suit one's own convenience; oblivious to the convenience of others" },
  { "question": "勤労奉仕", "answers": [ "きんろうほうし" ], "comment": "labor service; labour service" },
  { "question": "勧善懲悪", "answers": [ "かんぜんちょうあく" ], "comment": "rewarding good and punishing evil; novel or drama with a rewarding-good-and-punishing-evil theme; moral purpose; morality play" },
  { "question": "匍匐膝行", "answers": [ "ほふくしっこう" ] },
  { "question": "北斗七星", "answers": [ "ほくとしちせい" ], "comment": "the Big Dipper (asterism); the Plough; the Plow" },
  { "question": "医食同源", "answers": [ "いしょくどうげん" ], "comment": "a balanced diet leads to a healthy body; healthy food both prevents and cures sickness" },
  { "question": "十万億土", "answers": [ "じゅうまんおくど" ], "comment": "eternity; paradise" },
  { "question": "十中八九", "answers": [ "じっちゅうはっく" ], "comment": "in 8 or 9 cases out of ten; in all probability" },
  { "question": "十人十色", "answers": [ "じゅうにんといろ" ], "comment": "Several men, several minds; everyone has his own ideas and tastes; everyone has his own interests and ideas; different strokes for different folks" },
  { "question": "十字砲火", "answers": [ "じゅうじほうか" ], "comment": "cross fire" },
  { "question": "十年一日", "answers": [ "じゅうねんいちじつ" ], "comment": "without intermission for ten (long) years; with constancy of purpose for ten (long) years; in the same old rut for years on end" },
  { "question": "十年一昔", "answers": [ "じゅうねんひとむかし" ], "comment": "expression suggesting that the pace of change makes ten years back seem like ancient history" },
  { "question": "千万無量", "answers": [ "せんまんむりょう" ], "comment": "innumerable; unfathomable; unutterable" },
  { "question": "千両役者", "answers": [ "せんりょうやくしゃ" ], "comment": "star (actor); prima donna; leading figure" },
  { "question": "千乗万騎", "answers": [ "せんじょうばんき" ] },
  { "question": "千古万古", "answers": [ "せんこばんこ" ], "comment": "remote antiquity; ancient times; the remote past" },
  { "question": "千古不易", "answers": [ "せんこふえき" ], "comment": "eternally unchanging" },
  { "question": "千変万化", "answers": [ "せんぺんばんか" ], "comment": "innumerable changes; infinite variety" },
  { "question": "千姿万態", "answers": [ "せんしばんたい" ], "comment": "endless variety" },
  { "question": "千客万来", "answers": [ "せんきゃくばんらい" ], "comment": "flood of customers; (doing a) roaring business" },
  { "question": "千差万別", "answers": [ "せんさばんべつ" ], "comment": "an infinite variety of; multifarious; being extremely varied and wide-ranging" },
  { "question": "千思万考", "answers": [ "せんしばんこう" ], "comment": "deep meditation; mature consideration" },
  { "question": "千波万波", "answers": [ "せんぱばんぱ" ], "comment": "many waves; onrushing waves" },
  { "question": "千秋万歳", "answers": [ "せんしゅうばんざい" ] },
  { "question": "千篇一律", "answers": [ "せんぺんいちりつ" ], "comment": "monotonous; humdrum; stereotyped; banal; dull" },
  { "question": "千言万語", "answers": [ "せんげんばんご" ], "comment": "many words" },
  { "question": "千軍万馬", "answers": [ "せんぐんばんば" ], "comment": "(having experienced) many battles" },
  { "question": "千載一遇", "answers": [ "せんざいいちぐう" ], "comment": "once in a lifetime (opportunity); (a golden opportunity that may) happen only once in a thousand years" },
  { "question": "千辛万苦", "answers": [ "せんしんばんく" ], "comment": "many hardships" },
  { "question": "半信半疑", "answers": [ "はんしんはんぎ" ], "comment": "half in doubt; half-convinced; dubious; incredulous" },
  { "question": "半官半民", "answers": [ "はんかんはんみん" ], "comment": "semi-governmental; semi-official" },
  { "question": "半死半生", "answers": [ "はんしはんしょう" ], "comment": "all but dead; half killed" },
  { "question": "半睡半醒", "answers": [ "はんすいはんせい" ], "comment": "half asleep and half awake" },
  { "question": "半身不随", "answers": [ "はんしんふずい" ], "comment": "hemiplegia (paralysis on one side of the body)" },
  { "question": "半醒半睡", "answers": [ "はんせいはんすい" ], "comment": "half awake and half asleep" },
  { "question": "卑怯千万", "answers": [ "ひきょうせんばん" ], "comment": "very mean (sneaky); extremely unsportsmanlike" },
  { "question": "協心戮力", "answers": [ "きょうしんりくりょく" ], "comment": "combined (concerted) efforts; solidarity; joining forces (with)" },
  { "question": "南無三宝", "answers": [ "なむさんぼう" ], "comment": "Homage to the Three Jewels (Buddha, Dharma and Sangha)" },
  { "question": "南船北馬", "answers": [ "なんせんほくば" ], "comment": "constant travelling; constant traveling; being on the move; restless wandering" },
  { "question": "南蛮北狄", "answers": [ "なんばんほくてき" ] },
  { "question": "単刀直入", "answers": [ "たんとうちょくにゅう" ], "comment": "straight to the point; point-blank; frank; direct" },
  { "question": "単純明快", "answers": [ "たんじゅんめいかい" ], "comment": "simple and clear; plain and simple" },
  { "question": "博学多才", "answers": [ "はくがくたさい" ], "comment": "wide knowledge and versatile talents" },
  { "question": "博学多識", "answers": [ "はくがくたしき" ], "comment": "erudition and extensive knowledge" },
  { "question": "博引旁証", "answers": [ "はくいんぼうしょう" ], "comment": "citing copious references" },
  { "question": "博覧強記", "answers": [ "はくらんきょうき" ], "comment": "encyclopedic knowledge and strong memory" },
  { "question": "印象批評", "answers": [ "いんしょうひひょう" ], "comment": "impressionistic criticism" },
  { "question": "危急存亡", "answers": [ "ききゅうそんぼう" ], "comment": "life-and-death matter; an emergency or crisis where survival is threatened" },
  { "question": "危機一髪", "answers": [ "ききいっぱつ" ], "comment": "by a hair's breadth; in the nick of time; touch and go; close call; critical moment" },
  { "question": "即断即決", "answers": [ "そくだんそっけつ" ], "comment": "making a swift decision; making immediate decisions and taking quick actions" },
  { "question": "即決即断", "answers": [ "そっけつそくだん" ], "comment": "prompt decision and prompt execution; make swift decisions and take quick actions" },
  { "question": "即身成仏", "answers": [ "そくしんじょうぶつ" ], "comment": "attainment of Buddhahood during life" },
  { "question": "卿相雲客", "answers": [ "けいしょううんかく" ] },
  { "question": "厚顔無恥", "answers": [ "こうがんむち" ], "comment": "shameless; brazen and unscrupulous" },
  { "question": "厭離穢土", "answers": [ "おんりえど" ], "comment": "abhorrence of (living in) this impure world" },
  { "question": "厳正中立", "answers": [ "げんせいちゅうりつ" ], "comment": "strict neutrality" },
  { "question": "反目嫉視", "answers": [ "はんもくしっし" ], "comment": "jealousy and enmity; being jealous of and at odds with (each other)" },
  { "question": "反間苦肉", "answers": [ "はんかんくにく" ], "comment": "stratagem for causing a rift in the enemy camp by using a seditious plot" },
  { "question": "反面教師", "answers": [ "はんめんきょうし" ], "comment": "bad example from which one can learn; good example of what not to do (esp. how not to behave); negative example" },
  { "question": "取捨選択", "answers": [ "しゅしゃせんたく" ], "comment": "selection; making a choice; sifting; decision to adopt or reject" },
  { "question": "受胎告知", "answers": [ "じゅたいこくち" ], "comment": "the Annunciation" },
  { "question": "古今東西", "answers": [ "ここんとうざい" ], "comment": "all times and places; all ages and countries" },
  { "question": "古今無双", "answers": [ "ここんむそう" ], "comment": "unparalleled in history" },
  { "question": "古今独歩", "answers": [ "ここんどっぽ" ], "comment": "unsurpassed in history" },
  { "question": "古往今来", "answers": [ "こおうこんらい" ], "comment": "in all ages; since antiquity" },
  { "question": "古色蒼然", "answers": [ "こしょくそうぜん" ], "comment": "antique-looking; looking hoary with patina" },
  { "question": "只管打坐", "answers": [ "しかんたざ" ], "comment": "shikantaza (zazen meditation in which one focuses on sitting without actively seeking enlightenment)" },
  { "question": "叫喚地獄", "answers": [ "きょうかんじごく" ] },
  { "question": "台風一過", "answers": [ "たいふういっか" ], "comment": "clear weather after a typhoon has passed" },
  { "question": "叱咤激励", "answers": [ "しったげきれい" ], "comment": "giving a loud pep talk; encouraging (somebody) strongly in a loud voice" },
  { "question": "史上空前", "answers": [ "しじょうくうぜん" ], "comment": "unprecedented in history; unheard-of; epoch-making" },
  { "question": "右往左往", "answers": [ "うおうさおう" ], "comment": "moving about in confusion; going every which way; going this way and that" },
  { "question": "右顧左眄", "answers": [ "うこさべん" ], "comment": "looking to the right and left; hesitation" },
  { "question": "吃驚仰天", "answers": [ "きっきょうぎょうてん" ], "comment": "astonished; stunned; startled out of one's wits; thunderstruck; open-eyed astonishment" },
  { "question": "各人各様", "answers": [ "かくじんかくよう" ], "comment": "different strokes for different folks; people doing something in their own way" },
  { "question": "各種各様", "answers": [ "かくしゅかくよう" ], "comment": "individual (different) ways of doing things; being different (varied) for each item (type)" },
  { "question": "合従連衡", "answers": [ "がっしょうれんこう" ], "comment": "alliance (of the Six Kingdoms against the Qin dynasty, and of individual Kingdoms with the Qin dynasty)\n(tactic of) making & breaking alliances (to benefit oneself as the occasion demands); resorting to alliances as a diplomatic expedient" },
  { "question": "合縁奇縁", "answers": [ "あいえんきえん" ], "comment": "a couple strangely but happily united; uncanny relationship formed by a quirk of fate" },
  { "question": "吉凶禍福", "answers": [ "きっきょうかふく" ], "comment": "good and bad fortune, and weal and woe" },
  { "question": "同工異曲", "answers": [ "どうこういきょく" ], "comment": "equal workmanship but different style" },
  { "question": "同床異夢", "answers": [ "どうしょういむ" ], "comment": "cohabiting but living in different worlds" },
  { "question": "同気相求", "answers": [ "どうきそうきゅう" ] },
  { "question": "同病相憐", "answers": [ "どうびょうそうれん" ] },
  { "question": "名声籍甚", "answers": [ "めいせいせきじん" ] },
  { "question": "名字帯刀", "answers": [ "みょうじたいとう" ], "comment": "the right to bear a surname and to wear a sword (during the Edo period)" },
  { "question": "名所古跡", "answers": [ "めいしょこせき" ], "comment": "scenic sites and historic places; places of natural beauty and historic interest" },
  { "question": "名所旧跡", "answers": [ "めいしょきゅうせき" ], "comment": "scenic and historic places" },
  { "question": "名詮自性", "answers": [ "みょうせんじしょう" ] },
  { "question": "名誉挽回", "answers": [ "めいよばんかい" ], "comment": "restoring one's impaired reputation; regaining one's honor; redeeming oneself" },
  { "question": "名誉毀損", "answers": [ "めいよきそん" ], "comment": "libel; defamation; slander; character assassination" },
  { "question": "名論卓説", "answers": [ "めいろんたくせつ" ], "comment": "excellent opinions and theories" },
  { "question": "君子自重", "answers": [ "くんしじちょう" ] },
  { "question": "君子豹変", "answers": [ "くんしひょうへん" ], "comment": "the wise readily adapt themselves to changed circumstances; the wise are quick to acknowledge their mistakes and correct them\n(in colloquial usage, ironically or as an excuse) the wise make no scruple in suddenly changing their demeanor" },
  { "question": "呉越同舟", "answers": [ "ごえつどうしゅう" ], "comment": "bitter enemies (placed by fate) in the same boat" },
  { "question": "周知徹底", "answers": [ "しゅうちてってい" ], "comment": "dissemination; spreading of information" },
  { "question": "周章狼狽", "answers": [ "しゅうしょうろうばい" ], "comment": "consternation; fall into a panic; fluster oneself; dismay; discomfiture" },
  { "question": "呵呵大笑", "answers": [ "かかたいしょう" ], "comment": "laughing a ringing laugh; having a hearty laugh; roaring with laughter" },
  { "question": "和敬清寂", "answers": [ "わけいせいじゃく" ], "comment": "harmony, respect, purity and tranquility; the four most important elements of the tea ceremony" },
  { "question": "和気藹藹", "answers": [ "わきあいあい" ], "comment": "harmonious; peaceful; congenial" },
  { "question": "和洋折衷", "answers": [ "わようせっちゅう" ], "comment": "blending of Japanese and Western styles" },
  { "question": "品行方正", "answers": [ "ひんこうほうせい" ], "comment": "irreproachable conduct; good conduct; high morals" },
  { "question": "唇歯輔車", "answers": [ "しんしほしゃ" ], "comment": "mutual dependence" },
  { "question": "唯一無二", "answers": [ "ゆいいつむに" ], "comment": "one and only; unique" },
  { "question": "唯唯諾諾", "answers": [ "いいだくだく" ], "comment": "quite willingly; readily; with acquiescence" },
  { "question": "唯我独尊", "answers": [ "ゆいがどくそん" ], "comment": "self-conceit; self-centeredness; vainglory" },
  { "question": "商売繁盛", "answers": [ "しょうばいはんじょう" ], "comment": "thriving (prosperous) business; rush of business" },
  { "question": "問答無用", "answers": [ "もんどうむよう" ], "comment": "there being no use in arguing (about it)" },
  { "question": "問答無益", "answers": [ "もんどうむえき" ], "comment": "there being no use in arguing (about it); being stone-deaf to someone's appeals" },
  { "question": "善因善果", "answers": [ "ぜんいんぜんか" ], "comment": "good action lead to good rewards; one good turn deserves another" },
  { "question": "善後処置", "answers": [ "ぜんごしょち" ], "comment": "remedial measure; preventive measure; the best way to cope with (meet) the situation" },
  { "question": "善悪是非", "answers": [ "ぜんあくぜひ" ] },
  { "question": "善戦健闘", "answers": [ "ぜんせんけんとう" ] },
  { "question": "善男善女", "answers": [ "ぜんなんぜんにょ" ], "comment": "pious men and women" },
  { "question": "善隣外交", "answers": [ "ぜんりんがいこう" ], "comment": "good-neighbor diplomacy; a good-neighbor policy" },
  { "question": "喋喋喃喃", "answers": [ "ちょうちょうなんなん" ], "comment": "billing and cooing; holding an intimate, long-winded conversation in whispers" },
  { "question": "喜怒哀楽", "answers": [ "きどあいらく" ], "comment": "human emotions (joy, anger, pathos, and humor) (humour)" },
  { "question": "喜色満面", "answers": [ "きしょくまんめん" ], "comment": "being all smiles with joy" },
  { "question": "喧々囂々", "answers": [ "けんけんごうごう" ], "comment": "wild uproar; pandemonium; clamor of voices; tumult\nnoisy; uproarious; clamorous" },
  { "question": "喧々諤々", "answers": [ "けんけんがくがく" ], "comment": "tumultuous (with everyone voicing their opinions simultaneously); uproarious" },
  { "question": "器用貧乏", "answers": [ "きようびんぼう" ], "comment": "Jack of all trades and master of none" },
  { "question": "四六時中", "answers": [ "しろくじちゅう" ], "comment": "around the clock; day and night" },
  { "question": "四六駢儷", "answers": [ "しろくべんれい" ] },
  { "question": "四分五裂", "answers": [ "しぶんごれつ" ], "comment": "torn asunder; disrupted and disorganized" },
  { "question": "四方八方", "answers": [ "しほうはっぽう" ], "comment": "in all directions" },
  { "question": "四書五経", "answers": [ "ししょごきょう" ], "comment": "the Four Books and Five Classics of Confucianism; the Nine Chinese Classics" },
  { "question": "四海同胞", "answers": [ "しかいどうほう" ], "comment": "universal brotherhood" },
  { "question": "四海天下", "answers": [ "しかいてんか" ] },
  { "question": "四百四病", "answers": [ "しひゃくしびょう" ], "comment": "every type of disease" },
  { "question": "四神相応", "answers": [ "しじんそうおう" ], "comment": "an ideal topography for the four Taoist gods, with a river in the east, a broad avenue in the west, a basin in the south, and a hill in the north" },
  { "question": "四肢五体", "answers": [ "ししごたい" ], "comment": "the (one's) whole body" },
  { "question": "四苦八苦", "answers": [ "しくはっく" ], "comment": "being in dire distress; being hard put to it\nthe four and eight kinds of suffering" },
  { "question": "四角四面", "answers": [ "しかくしめん" ], "comment": "square; formal" },
  { "question": "四通八達", "answers": [ "しつうはったつ" ], "comment": "traffic network extending in all directions" },
  { "question": "四面楚歌", "answers": [ "しめんそか" ], "comment": "being surrounded by enemies on all sides; being betrayed (forsaken) by everybody" },
  { "question": "因循姑息", "answers": [ "いんじゅんこそく" ], "comment": "dilly-dallying and temporizing (temporising)" },
  { "question": "因果因縁", "answers": [ "いんがいんねん" ], "comment": "cause and effect; karma; retribution; an evil cause producing an evil effect" },
  { "question": "因果応報", "answers": [ "いんがおうほう" ], "comment": "retribution; retributive justice; karma; just deserts; poetic justice; reward and punishment for one's past behavior" },
  { "question": "困苦欠乏", "answers": [ "こんくけつぼう" ], "comment": "hardships and privations" },
  { "question": "困苦窮乏", "answers": [ "こんくきゅうぼう" ], "comment": "hardships and privations" },
  { "question": "固定観念", "answers": [ "こていかんねん" ], "comment": "fixed idea; idee fixe; stereotype; prejudice" },
  { "question": "国士無双", "answers": [ "こくしむそう" ], "comment": "distinguished person\nthirteen orphans; winning hand containing one of each terminal and honor tile plus one extra copy of any of them" },
  { "question": "国威発揚", "answers": [ "こくいはつよう" ], "comment": "enhancing national prestige; expanding national influence" },
  { "question": "国民主権", "answers": [ "こくみんしゅけん" ], "comment": "sovereignty of the people" },
  { "question": "在留邦人", "answers": [ "ざいりゅうほうじん" ], "comment": "Japanese residents in another country; Japanese expatriates" },
  { "question": "地水火風", "answers": [ "ちすいかふう" ], "comment": "earth, water, fire, and wind (the four elements)" },
  { "question": "地盤沈下", "answers": [ "じばんちんか" ], "comment": "land subsidence\ndecline in influence" },
  { "question": "坐作進退", "answers": [ "ざさしんたい" ], "comment": "deportment; behavior; carriage" },
  { "question": "垂直思考", "answers": [ "すいちょくしこう" ], "comment": "rigid (stereotypical) thinking that adheres to preconceived notions" },
  { "question": "執行猶予", "answers": [ "しっこうゆうよ" ], "comment": "stay of execution; suspended sentence" },
  { "question": "堂塔伽藍", "answers": [ "どうとうがらん" ] },
  { "question": "堅忍不抜", "answers": [ "けんにんふばつ" ], "comment": "indomitable perseverance; invincible fortitude" },
  { "question": "墨痕淋漓", "answers": [ "ぼっこんりんり" ], "comment": "dripping ink marks; a work of calligraphy being written in bold and vivid strokes" },
  { "question": "士気高揚", "answers": [ "しきこうよう" ], "comment": "raise (lift) morale; have an inspiring effect on morale" },
  { "question": "士農工商", "answers": [ "しのうこうしょう" ], "comment": "hierarchy of samurai, farmers, artisans, and merchants in Edo society" },
  { "question": "変幻自在", "answers": [ "へんげんじざい" ], "comment": "phantasmagoric; capable of ever-changing appearance" },
  { "question": "変態百出", "answers": [ "へんたいひゃくしゅつ" ] },
  { "question": "外交辞令", "answers": [ "がいこうじれい" ], "comment": "diplomatic turn of phrase; diplomatic language; tactful way of expressing something" },
  { "question": "外柔内剛", "answers": [ "がいじゅうないごう" ], "comment": "gentle but firm" },
  { "question": "多事多端", "answers": [ "たじたたん" ], "comment": "eventfulness; pressure of business" },
  { "question": "多事多難", "answers": [ "たじたなん" ], "comment": "various difficulties" },
  { "question": "多士済々", "answers": [ "たしせいせい" ], "comment": "galaxy of able persons; collection of intellectuals" },
  { "question": "多情仏心", "answers": [ "たじょうぶっしん" ], "comment": "fickle but kind-hearted" },
  { "question": "多情多恨", "answers": [ "たじょうたこん" ], "comment": "going through life with one's heart on one's sleeve; sensibility" },
  { "question": "多情多感", "answers": [ "たじょうたかん" ], "comment": "sentimental; being full of emotions; having tender sensibilities" },
  { "question": "多感多恨", "answers": [ "たかんたこん" ] },
  { "question": "多種多様", "answers": [ "たしゅたよう" ], "comment": "a great variety of; diversity" },
  { "question": "夜目遠目", "answers": [ "よめとおめ" ], "comment": "seen in the dark or at a distance; (a woman) looking prettier when seen in the dark or at a distance" },
  { "question": "夜郎自大", "answers": [ "やろうじだい" ], "comment": "throwing one's weight around in a small group without knowing one's real worth in a larger world outside; being a big fish in a small pond" },
  { "question": "大兵肥満", "answers": [ "だいひょうひまん" ], "comment": "big portly man" },
  { "question": "大千世界", "answers": [ "だいせんせかい" ] },
  { "question": "大同団結", "answers": [ "だいどうだんけつ" ], "comment": "merger; (presenting a) united front" },
  { "question": "大同小異", "answers": [ "だいどうしょうい" ], "comment": "essentially the same with only minor differences" },
  { "question": "大和撫子", "answers": [ "やまとなでしこ" ], "comment": "large pink (Dianthus superbus var. longicalycinus)\nwoman who displays the feminine virtues of old Japan" },
  { "question": "大喝一声", "answers": [ "だいかついっせい" ], "comment": "shouting in a thunderous voice; blustering out" },
  { "question": "大器晩成", "answers": [ "たいきばんせい" ], "comment": "Great talents mature late" },
  { "question": "大安吉日", "answers": [ "たいあんきちじつ" ], "comment": "very auspicious day for all types of occasions (one of the six special days in the Japanese lunisolar calendar)" },
  { "question": "大山鳴動", "answers": [ "たいざんめいどう" ], "comment": "big fuss over nothing; much cry and little wool; much ado about nothing" },
  { "question": "大廈高楼", "answers": [ "たいかこうろう" ], "comment": "large building and lofty tower; splendid (magnificent, palatial) structure" },
  { "question": "大悟徹底", "answers": [ "たいごてってい" ], "comment": "attain divine enlightenment; perceive absolute truth; experience spiritual awakening" },
  { "question": "大慈大悲", "answers": [ "だいじだいひ" ], "comment": "great compassion and mercy" },
  { "question": "大慶至極", "answers": [ "たいけいしごく" ] },
  { "question": "大所高所", "answers": [ "たいしょこうしょ" ], "comment": "broad perspective" },
  { "question": "大政奉還", "answers": [ "たいせいほうかん" ], "comment": "restoration of imperial rule" },
  { "question": "大死一番", "answers": [ "だいしいちばん" ], "comment": "exerting oneself to the utmost, prepared to die if necessary" },
  { "question": "大盤振舞", "answers": [ "おおばんぶるまい" ], "comment": "lavish feast; splendid banquet\ncorporate largess; lavish hospitality" },
  { "question": "大義名分", "answers": [ "たいぎめいぶん" ], "comment": "a just cause" },
  { "question": "大義滅親", "answers": [ "たいぎめっしん" ] },
  { "question": "大胆不敵", "answers": [ "だいたんふてき" ], "comment": "audacity; daredevil (attitude)" },
  { "question": "大言壮語", "answers": [ "たいげんそうご" ], "comment": "big talk; boasting; bragging" },
  { "question": "大逆無道", "answers": [ "たいぎゃくむどう" ], "comment": "heinous; treacherous; atrocious; diabolic; fiendish; inhuman" },
  { "question": "大願成就", "answers": [ "たいがんじょうじゅ" ], "comment": "realization of a great ambition; realisation of a great ambition" },
  { "question": "天上人間", "answers": [ "てんじょうじんかん" ] },
  { "question": "天上天下", "answers": [ "てんじょうてんげ" ], "comment": "the whole world; throughout heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天下一品", "answers": [ "てんかいっぴん" ], "comment": "best article under heaven; peerless" },
  { "question": "天下御免", "answers": [ "てんかごめん" ], "comment": "licensed; chartered; officially allowed; legitimate" },
  { "question": "天下泰平", "answers": [ "てんかたいへい" ], "comment": "peaceful and tranquil (uneventful); peace reigns over the land; halcyon times of peace" },
  { "question": "天下無双", "answers": [ "てんかむそう" ], "comment": "peerless; unequaled; unequalled" },
  { "question": "天下無敵", "answers": [ "てんかむてき" ], "comment": "peerless; unequalled; unequaled" },
  { "question": "天下無類", "answers": [ "てんかむるい" ], "comment": "peerless (unparalleled, matchless, unequaled) in the country" },
  { "question": "天井桟敷", "answers": [ "てんじょうさじき" ], "comment": "gallery (in a theatre); upper gallery; cheap seats; nosebleed section; the gods" },
  { "question": "天佑神助", "answers": [ "てんゆうしんじょ" ], "comment": "divine grace; God's help" },
  { "question": "天叢雲剣", "answers": [ "あめのむらくものつるぎ" ], "comment": "Ama-no-Murakumo no Tsurugi (heavenly gathering of clouds sword; one of the three Imperial regalia)" },
  { "question": "天地万有", "answers": [ "てんちばんゆう" ] },
  { "question": "天地万物", "answers": [ "てんちばんぶつ" ], "comment": "the whole creation; everything in heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天地無用", "answers": [ "てんちむよう" ], "comment": "do not turn upside down" },
  { "question": "天地玄黄", "answers": [ "てんちげんこう" ], "comment": "Heaven is black and earth is yellow; heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天地神明", "answers": [ "てんちしんめい" ], "comment": "the gods of heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天地開闢", "answers": [ "てんちかいびゃく" ], "comment": "creation of heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天壌無窮", "answers": [ "てんじょうむきゅう" ], "comment": "as eternal as heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天変地異", "answers": [ "てんぺんちい" ], "comment": "natural disaster; cataclysm" },
  { "question": "天孫降臨", "answers": [ "てんそんこうりん" ], "comment": "the descent to earth of the grandson of the sun goddess" },
  { "question": "天涯地角", "answers": [ "てんがいちかく" ], "comment": "two places being far apart" },
  { "question": "天涯孤独", "answers": [ "てんがいこどく" ], "comment": "a person without a single relative" },
  { "question": "天災地変", "answers": [ "てんさいちへん" ], "comment": "natural disaster" },
  { "question": "天然自然", "answers": [ "てんねんしぜん" ], "comment": "natural\nnaturally" },
  { "question": "天真爛漫", "answers": [ "てんしんらんまん" ], "comment": "naivete; simplicity; innocence" },
  { "question": "天神地祇", "answers": [ "てんしんちぎ" ], "comment": "gods of heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天空海闊", "answers": [ "てんくうかいかつ" ], "comment": "the open sky and the serene sea; as open as the sky and serene as the sea; magnanimous" },
  { "question": "天網恢恢", "answers": [ "てんもうかいかい" ], "comment": "heaven's vengeance is slow but sure; heaven's net is wide and coarse, yet nothing slips through" },
  { "question": "天罰覿面", "answers": [ "てんばつてきめん" ], "comment": "the certainty of divine punishment; Swift is Heaven's vengeance" },
  { "question": "天衣無縫", "answers": [ "てんいむほう" ], "comment": "perfect beauty with no trace of artifice; flawless" },
  { "question": "天長地久", "answers": [ "てんちょうちきゅう" ], "comment": "coeval with heaven and earth" },
  { "question": "天魔波旬", "answers": [ "てんまはじゅん" ] },
  { "question": "太液芙蓉", "answers": [ "たいえきのふよう" ] },
  { "question": "夫唱婦随", "answers": [ "ふしょうふずい" ], "comment": "a wife should do her husband's bidding" },
  { "question": "失地回復", "answers": [ "しっちかいふく" ], "comment": "the recovery of lost territory; recovering (regaining) lost ground (one's former position); fence-mending" },
  { "question": "失敬千万", "answers": [ "しっけいせんばん" ], "comment": "extremely rude (impertinent, impolite)" },
  { "question": "失望落胆", "answers": [ "しつぼうらくたん" ], "comment": "being disappointed and disheartened" },
  { "question": "失礼千万", "answers": [ "しつれいせんばん" ], "comment": "extremely rude (impertinent, impolite)" },
  { "question": "奇奇怪怪", "answers": [ "ききかいかい" ], "comment": "very strange; bizarre; weird; mysterious" },
  { "question": "奇怪千万", "answers": [ "きかいせんばん" ], "comment": "very strange (mysterious, weird); bizarre; monstrous; outrageous" },
  { "question": "奇想天外", "answers": [ "きそうてんがい" ], "comment": "fantastic; bizarre; incredible; unbelievable" },
  { "question": "奔放不羈", "answers": [ "ほんぽうふき" ], "comment": "free-spirited and uninhibited" },
  { "question": "奮励努力", "answers": [ "ふんれいどりょく" ], "comment": "making strenuous efforts; exerting oneself" },
  { "question": "奮闘努力", "answers": [ "ふんとうどりょく" ], "comment": "try one's best; all-out effort; strenuous efforts" },
  { "question": "女人禁制", "answers": [ "にょにんきんせい" ], "comment": "prohibited to women (usu. for religious reasons); no women admitted" },
  { "question": "女尊男卑", "answers": [ "じょそんだんぴ" ], "comment": "placing women above men" },
  { "question": "奸佞邪智", "answers": [ "かんねいじゃち" ], "comment": "wiles and cunning; craftiness and treachery" },
  { "question": "好機到来", "answers": [ "こうきとうらい" ], "comment": "advent of a golden opportunity" },
  { "question": "如意宝珠", "answers": [ "にょいほうじゅ" ], "comment": "Cintamani stone; wish-fulfilling jewel" },
  { "question": "如是我聞", "answers": [ "にょぜがもん" ], "comment": "thus I hear (quote from the sutras); these ears have heard" },
  { "question": "妄言多謝", "answers": [ "もうげんたしゃ" ], "comment": "Kindly excuse my reckless remarks; Please excuse my thoughtless words. (used deferentially, in a letter, etc.)" },
  { "question": "妖怪変化", "answers": [ "ようかいへんげ" ], "comment": "(animal making a) monstrous apparition" },
  { "question": "妻子眷族", "answers": [ "さいしけんぞく" ] },
  { "question": "威風堂々", "answers": [ "いふうどうどう" ], "comment": "being majestic; with great pomp and circumstance; with an imposing air" },
  { "question": "子子孫孫", "answers": [ "ししそんそん" ], "comment": "one's descendants; one's offspring; posterity" },
  { "question": "孟母三遷", "answers": [ "もうぼさんせん" ], "comment": "the importance of creating an environment conducive to a child's learning; Mencius' mother, three moves" },
  { "question": "孤城落日", "answers": [ "こじょうらくじつ" ], "comment": "feeling (looking) lone and helpless; helplessness of those in reduced circumstances" },
  { "question": "孤立無援", "answers": [ "こりつむえん" ], "comment": "being isolated and helpless; fighting (struggling) alone and unassisted" },
  { "question": "孤軍奮闘", "answers": [ "こぐんふんとう" ], "comment": "fighting alone" },
  { "question": "安心立命", "answers": [ "あんじんりつめい" ], "comment": "spiritual peace and enlightenment; keeping an unperturbed mind through faith" },
  { "question": "完全無欠", "answers": [ "かんぜんむけつ" ], "comment": "flawless; absolute perfection" },
  { "question": "完全燃焼", "answers": [ "かんぜんねんしょう" ], "comment": "perfect combustion" },
  { "question": "宏大無辺", "answers": [ "こうだいむへん" ] },
  { "question": "宛転蛾眉", "answers": [ "えんてんがび" ] },
  { "question": "実力伯仲", "answers": [ "じつりょくはくちゅう" ], "comment": "(the two persons' sides) being evenly matched in ability" },
  { "question": "宣戦布告", "answers": [ "せんせんふこく" ], "comment": "declaration of war; proclamation of war" },
  { "question": "家族団欒", "answers": [ "かぞくだんらん" ], "comment": "happy family circle; sitting in a family circle and enjoying conversation; harmony in a family" },
  { "question": "容姿端麗", "answers": [ "ようしたんれい" ], "comment": "attractive face and figure" },
  { "question": "容貌魁偉", "answers": [ "ようぼうかいい" ], "comment": "(a man) having a commanding face and a powerful physique" },
  { "question": "寂滅為楽", "answers": [ "じゃくめついらく" ], "comment": "Freedom from one's desires (Entry into Nirvana) is true bliss" },
  { "question": "富国強兵", "answers": [ "ふこくきょうへい" ], "comment": "wealth and military strength of a country; \"rich country, strong army\": a slogan from the Meiji era referring to the government's goals for the country" },
  { "question": "寛仁大度", "answers": [ "かんじんたいど" ], "comment": "being generous, benevolent and magnanimous in disposition" },
  { "question": "寡頭政治", "answers": [ "かとうせいじ" ], "comment": "oligarchy" },
  { "question": "専売特許", "answers": [ "せんばいとっきょ" ], "comment": "patent\none's specialty (party piece, etc.)" },
  { "question": "尊皇攘夷", "answers": [ "そんのうじょうい" ], "comment": "19th century slogan advocating reverence for the Emperor and the expulsion of (barbarian) foreigners" },
  { "question": "尋常一様", "answers": [ "じんじょういちよう" ], "comment": "ordinary; common; mediocre" },
  { "question": "小人閑居", "answers": [ "しょうじんかんきょ" ], "comment": "a small-minded person being idle (tends to do evil)" },
  { "question": "小心翼翼", "answers": [ "しょうしんよくよく" ], "comment": "very timid; very nervous; faint-hearted" },
  { "question": "小春日和", "answers": [ "こはるびより" ], "comment": "Indian summer (around November); mild late autumn weather; mild late fall weather" },
  { "question": "少壮気鋭", "answers": [ "しょうそうきえい" ], "comment": "young and energetic; up-and-coming" },
  { "question": "少数精鋭", "answers": [ "しょうすうせいえい" ], "comment": "elect (select) few" },
  { "question": "尽忠報国", "answers": [ "じんちゅうほうこく" ], "comment": "loyalty and patriotism" },
  { "question": "尽未来際", "answers": [ "じんみらいさい" ], "comment": "to the end of time; to the crack of doom; for ever and ever" },
  { "question": "局外中立", "answers": [ "きょくがいちゅうりつ" ], "comment": "neutrality" },
  { "question": "局面打開", "answers": [ "きょくめんだかい" ], "comment": "breakthrough in the situation; break in the deadlocked situation" },
  { "question": "屍山血河", "answers": [ "しざんけつが" ], "comment": "heaps of bodies and streams of blood; fierce battle" },
  { "question": "山川草木", "answers": [ "さんせんそうもく" ], "comment": "nature; natural scenery" },
  { "question": "山海珍味", "answers": [ "さんかいのちんみ" ] },
  { "question": "山窮水尽", "answers": [ "さんきゅうすいじん" ] },
  { "question": "山紫水明", "answers": [ "さんしすいめい" ], "comment": "scenic beauty" },
  { "question": "岡目八目", "answers": [ "おかめはちもく" ], "comment": "bystander's vantage point; outsider's better grasp of the situation\nonlookers see more of the game than the players do; people watching a game of go see 8 moves further ahead" },
  { "question": "左見右見", "answers": [ "とみこうみ" ], "comment": "looking to and fro" },
  { "question": "巧言令色", "answers": [ "こうげんれいしょく" ], "comment": "flattery; honeyed words" },
  { "question": "巫山雲雨", "answers": [ "ふざんうんう" ], "comment": "sexual liaison" },
  { "question": "希少価値", "answers": [ "きしょうかち" ], "comment": "scarcity value; rarity value; preciousness" },
  { "question": "師資相承", "answers": [ "ししそうしょう" ], "comment": "generation-to-generation instruction from master to disciple" },
  { "question": "帰命頂礼", "answers": [ "きみょうちょうらい" ] },
  { "question": "帰巣本能", "answers": [ "きそうほんのう" ], "comment": "homing instinct" },
  { "question": "常住坐臥", "answers": [ "じょうじゅうざが" ], "comment": "at all times; day in, day out; constantly; always" },
  { "question": "常在戦場", "answers": [ "じょうざいせんじょう" ], "comment": "always conducting oneself as though one were on a battlefield; being combat ready at all times (of a person)" },
  { "question": "常套手段", "answers": [ "じょうとうしゅだん" ], "comment": "one's habitual practice; usual measure; old trick" },
  { "question": "干将莫耶", "answers": [ "かんしょうばくや" ] },
  { "question": "平和共存", "answers": [ "へいわきょうぞん" ], "comment": "peaceful coexistence" },
  { "question": "平平凡凡", "answers": [ "へいへいぼんぼん" ], "comment": "very ordinary; mediocre; all-too-common; quite commonplace" },
  { "question": "平穏無事", "answers": [ "へいおんぶじ" ], "comment": "tranquillity and peace; tranquility and peace; peaceful and uneventful" },
  { "question": "平等平等", "answers": [ "へらへいとう" ] },
  { "question": "平衡感覚", "answers": [ "へいこうかんかく" ], "comment": "sense of equilibrium; sense of balance" },
  { "question": "平身低頭", "answers": [ "へいしんていとう" ], "comment": "prostrating oneself; kowtowing; going down on one's knees" },
  { "question": "年中行事", "answers": [ "ねんちゅうぎょうじ" ], "comment": "annual function; annual event" },
  { "question": "年功序列", "answers": [ "ねんこうじょれつ" ], "comment": "seniority by length of service" },
  { "question": "年年歳歳", "answers": [ "ねんねんさいさい" ], "comment": "annually; every year; year in year out; from year to year" },
  { "question": "年百年中", "answers": [ "ねんびゃくねんじゅう" ], "comment": "throughout the year; all the year round; always" },
  { "question": "廃仏毀釈", "answers": [ "はいぶつきしゃく" ], "comment": "anti-Buddhist movement at the beginning of the Meiji era" },
  { "question": "廃藩置県", "answers": [ "はいはんちけん" ], "comment": "abolition of feudal domains and establishment of prefectures (1871)" },
  { "question": "廓然無聖", "answers": [ "かくねんむしょう" ] },
  { "question": "延命息災", "answers": [ "えんめいそくさい" ], "comment": "health and longevity; enjoying a long and healthy life being untouched by disaster" },
  { "question": "弊衣破帽", "answers": [ "へいいはぼう" ], "comment": "shabby clothes and an old hat" },
  { "question": "弱肉強食", "answers": [ "じゃくにくきょうしょく" ], "comment": "survival of the fittest; the law of the jungle; the weak are meat the strong do eat" },
  { "question": "強情我慢", "answers": [ "ごうじょうがまん" ], "comment": "obstinate and self-assertive" },
  { "question": "強硬手段", "answers": [ "きょうこうしゅだん" ], "comment": "tough measure; firm step; strong measure" },
  { "question": "強迫観念", "answers": [ "きょうはくかんねん" ], "comment": "obsession; unreasonable but compulsive idea" },
  { "question": "当代無双", "answers": [ "とうだいむそう" ], "comment": "being unsurpassed (unparalleled) at present" },
  { "question": "当意即妙", "answers": [ "とういそくみょう" ], "comment": "ready wit" },
  { "question": "彫心鏤骨", "answers": [ "ちょうしんるこつ" ], "comment": "laborious work; lucubration; lucubrations; painstakingly polishing a piece of literary work" },
  { "question": "往古来今", "answers": [ "おうこらいこん" ] },
  { "question": "待対世界", "answers": [ "たいたいせかい" ] },
  { "question": "後生大事", "answers": [ "ごしょうだいじ" ], "comment": "with religious zeal; with utmost devotion; take great care of" },
  { "question": "後生菩提", "answers": [ "ごしょうぼだい" ] },
  { "question": "徒手空拳", "answers": [ "としゅくうけん" ], "comment": "empty-handed; with nothing to start with; without capital" },
  { "question": "得意満面", "answers": [ "とくいまんめん" ], "comment": "triumphant air; smugness" },
  { "question": "得手勝手", "answers": [ "えてかって" ], "comment": "self-willed; (doing or saying things) to suit one's own convenience" },
  { "question": "御用繁多", "answers": [ "ごようはんた" ], "comment": "being busy with many things; extreme busyness due to pressure of business (often used humorously)" },
  { "question": "徹頭徹尾", "answers": [ "てっとうてつび" ], "comment": "thoroughly; through and through" },
  { "question": "徹骨徹髄", "answers": [ "てっこつてつずい" ] },
  { "question": "心外千万", "answers": [ "しんがいせんばん" ], "comment": "being totally upset (by); being completely nonplused (by); being mortified (at); feeling aggrieved (at); finding (it) highly regrettable" },
  { "question": "心悸亢進", "answers": [ "しんきこうしん" ], "comment": "palpitations (of the heart)" },
  { "question": "心機一転", "answers": [ "しんきいってん" ], "comment": "changing one's attitude; turning over a new leaf; getting a fresh start" },
  { "question": "心神喪失", "answers": [ "しんしんそうしつ" ], "comment": "of unsound mind" },
  { "question": "心神耗弱", "answers": [ "しんしんこうじゃく" ], "comment": "diminished capacity; diminished responsibility; legally unaccountable (e.g. due to mental illness, drugs, alcohol, etc.)" },
  { "question": "心象風景", "answers": [ "しんしょうふうけい" ], "comment": "imagined landscape; scenery in one's mind's eye" },
  { "question": "心頭滅却", "answers": [ "しんとうめっきゃく" ], "comment": "clearing one's mind of all mundane thoughts" },
  { "question": "志操堅固", "answers": [ "しそうけんご" ], "comment": "being faithful to one's principles; being of firm purpose and deep commitment; constancy; true blue" },
  { "question": "応急措置", "answers": [ "おうきゅうそち" ], "comment": "stopgap measure; quick-fix solution" },
  { "question": "忠信孝悌", "answers": [ "ちゅうしんこうてい" ] },
  { "question": "忠勇無双", "answers": [ "ちゅうゆうむそう" ], "comment": "of peerless loyalty and bravery" },
  { "question": "忠勇義烈", "answers": [ "ちゅうゆうぎれつ" ] },
  { "question": "忠君愛国", "answers": [ "ちゅうくんあいこく" ], "comment": "loyalty and patriotism" },
  { "question": "快刀乱麻", "answers": [ "かいとうらんま" ], "comment": "solving a problem swiftly and skillfully" },
  { "question": "念仏三昧", "answers": [ "ねんぶつざんまい" ], "comment": "being deep in prayer; praying devoutly to Amida Buddha" },
  { "question": "思慮分別", "answers": [ "しりょふんべつ" ], "comment": "discrete and well-advised judgment; wise and mature judgment; making judgment with prudence" },
  { "question": "思案投首", "answers": [ "しあんなげくび" ], "comment": "being at one's wit's end; being (quite) at a loss (what to do)" },
  { "question": "急転直下", "answers": [ "きゅうてんちょっか" ], "comment": "suddenly and precipitately; take a sudden turn" },
  { "question": "怨憎会苦", "answers": [ "おんぞうえく" ], "comment": "the pain of meeting people one dislikes" },
  { "question": "怨敵退散", "answers": [ "おんてきたいさん" ], "comment": "invoking disaster upon one's mortal enemy; Confusion to the enemy!" },
  { "question": "怪力乱神", "answers": [ "かいりきらんしん" ], "comment": "supernatural things; unnatural phenomena; spirits and demons" },
  { "question": "恐悦至極", "answers": [ "きょうえつしごく" ], "comment": "extremely delighted" },
  { "question": "恐惶謹言", "answers": [ "きょうこうきんげん" ], "comment": "Very truly yours (a complimentary close used in a letter written in an old epistolary style)" },
  { "question": "恒久平和", "answers": [ "こうきゅうへいわ" ] },
  { "question": "息災延命", "answers": [ "そくさいえんめい" ], "comment": "health and longevity; enjoying a long and healthy life being untouched by disaster" },
  { "question": "悉有仏性", "answers": [ "しつうぶっしょう" ] },
  { "question": "悉皆成仏", "answers": [ "しっかいじょうぶつ" ], "comment": "all things have the Buddha nature" },
  { "question": "悖徳没倫", "answers": [ "はいとくぼつりん" ] },
  { "question": "悠悠自適", "answers": [ "ゆうゆうじてき" ], "comment": "living a life of leisure with dignity; living quietly and comfortably free from worldly cares; otium cum dignitate" },
  { "question": "悪事千里", "answers": [ "あくじせんり" ], "comment": "bad news traveling fast; ill news spreading like wildfire" },
  { "question": "悪口雑言", "answers": [ "あっこうぞうごん" ], "comment": "all kinds of malicious gossip; heaping verbal abuse (on); cursing and swearing (words)" },
  { "question": "悪因悪果", "answers": [ "あくいんあっか" ], "comment": "sowing and reaping evil" },
  { "question": "悪戦苦闘", "answers": [ "あくせんくとう" ], "comment": "hard fighting; hard struggle; fighting against heavy odds" },
  { "question": "悪逆無道", "answers": [ "あくぎゃくむどう" ], "comment": "treacherous; heinous; treasonous; atrocious" },
  { "question": "悪逆非道", "answers": [ "あくぎゃくひどう" ], "comment": "heinous; treacherous; atrocious; diabolic; fiendish; inhuman" },
  { "question": "悪鬼羅刹", "answers": [ "あっきらせつ" ], "comment": "man-eating fiend" },
  { "question": "悲憤慷慨", "answers": [ "ひふんこうがい" ], "comment": "indignant lamentation over the evils of the times" },
  { "question": "悶絶躄地", "answers": [ "もんぜつびゃくじ" ] },
  { "question": "情状酌量", "answers": [ "じょうじょうしゃくりょう" ], "comment": "taking the extenuating circumstances into consideration" },
  { "question": "情緒纏綿", "answers": [ "じょうしょてんめん" ], "comment": "tender sentiments; being overcome with emotions; having a tender feeling (for a person)" },
  { "question": "意到筆随", "answers": [ "いとうひつずい" ] },
  { "question": "意味深長", "answers": [ "いみしんちょう" ], "comment": "with profound (often hidden) meaning; being suggestive; pregnant with significance" },
  { "question": "意志堅固", "answers": [ "いしけんご" ], "comment": "strong determination; strong-willed; having strong will power; firmness of purpose" },
  { "question": "意志薄弱", "answers": [ "いしはくじゃく" ], "comment": "weak-willed; lacking a purpose; lacking will power to be patient, purposeful, or resolute" },
  { "question": "意思表示", "answers": [ "いしひょうじ" ], "comment": "declaration of intent; declaration of intention; expression of one's intention; manifestation of intention" },
  { "question": "意気投合", "answers": [ "いきとうごう" ], "comment": "hit it off with (a person); find a kindred spirit in (a person); sympathy; mutual understanding" },
  { "question": "意気揚揚", "answers": [ "いきようよう" ], "comment": "triumphant; exultant; in high and proud spirits" },
  { "question": "意気沮喪", "answers": [ "いきそそう" ], "comment": "depressed in spirits; rejection; disheartened; lacking nerve" },
  { "question": "意気衝天", "answers": [ "いきしょうてん" ], "comment": "in high spirits" },
  { "question": "意気軒昂", "answers": [ "いきけんこう" ], "comment": "in high spirits; elated" },
  { "question": "意気銷沈", "answers": [ "いきしょうちん" ], "comment": "depressed in spirits; dispirited; disheartened; rejection" },
  { "question": "意識朦朧", "answers": [ "いしきもうろう" ], "comment": "being in a hazy state; being only half conscious; feeling dopey" },
  { "question": "意趣遺恨", "answers": [ "いしゅいこん" ], "comment": "grudge; spite; malice; rancor" },
  { "question": "意馬心猿", "answers": [ "いばしんえん" ], "comment": "it is hard to keep one's worldly desires and passions in check" },
  { "question": "愚問愚答", "answers": [ "ぐもんぐとう" ], "comment": "silly questions and silly answers; a silly dialogue" },
  { "question": "愛別離苦", "answers": [ "あいべつりく" ], "comment": "the pain of separation from loved ones" },
  { "question": "感奮興起", "answers": [ "かんぷんこうき" ] },
  { "question": "感情移入", "answers": [ "かんじょういにゅう" ], "comment": "empathy" },
  { "question": "感慨無量", "answers": [ "かんがいむりょう" ], "comment": "deep emotion; one's mind is filled with thousand emotions" },
  { "question": "慇懃無礼", "answers": [ "いんぎんぶれい" ], "comment": "hypocritical courtesy; superficially polite but rude in intent" },
  { "question": "慎重居士", "answers": [ "しんちょうこじ" ], "comment": "very cautious person; very prudent person; very discreet person" },
  { "question": "慮外千万", "answers": [ "りょがいせんばん" ] },
  { "question": "懇切丁寧", "answers": [ "こんせつていねい" ], "comment": "(an explanation, advice, etc. being) kind, careful, and thorough" },
  { "question": "懐玉有罪", "answers": [ "かいぎょくゆうざい" ] },
  { "question": "懸軍万里", "answers": [ "けんぐんばんり" ], "comment": "military expedition deep into enemy territory" },
  { "question": "我武者羅", "answers": [ "がむしゃら" ], "comment": "reckless; daredevil; frantic" },
  { "question": "我田引水", "answers": [ "がでんいんすい" ], "comment": "seeking one's own interests; straining (the interpretation or argument) to suit one's own interests; drawing water for one's own field" },
  { "question": "戦意喪失", "answers": [ "せんいそうしつ" ], "comment": "losing one's fighting spirit; losing the will to fight; losing heart" },
  { "question": "戦戦兢兢", "answers": [ "せんせんきょうきょう" ], "comment": "trembling with fear; filled with trepidation" },
  { "question": "戮力協心", "answers": [ "りくりょくきょうしん" ], "comment": "combined (concerted) efforts; solidarity; joining forces (with)" },
  { "question": "戯作三昧", "answers": [ "げさくざんまい" ], "comment": "being absorbed in writing popular novels (cheap fiction); being absorbed in writing something to amuse oneself" },
  { "question": "手前勝手", "answers": [ "てまえがって" ], "comment": "self-centered; self-centred; selfish" },
  { "question": "手前味噌", "answers": [ "てまえみそ" ], "comment": "self-flattery; sing one's own praises" },
  { "question": "手枷足枷", "answers": [ "てかせあしかせ" ], "comment": "manacles; shackles; fetters" },
  { "question": "手練手管", "answers": [ "てれんてくだ" ], "comment": "wiles; art of coaxing" },
  { "question": "才子佳人", "answers": [ "さいしかじん" ], "comment": "talented man and a beautiful woman; well-matched pair; wit and beauty" },
  { "question": "才気煥発", "answers": [ "さいきかんぱつ" ], "comment": "quick-witted; a flash of brilliance; great wisdom" },
  { "question": "才色兼備", "answers": [ "さいしょくけんび" ], "comment": "(a woman) being gifted with both intelligence and beauty" },
  { "question": "打草驚蛇", "answers": [ "だそうきょうだ" ] },
  { "question": "抜山蓋世", "answers": [ "ばつざんがいせい" ], "comment": "great strength and energy (of a mighty hero); Herculean strength and vitality" },
  { "question": "拈華微笑", "answers": [ "ねんげみしょう" ], "comment": "heart-to-heart communication; thought transference; holding a flower and subtly smiling" },
  { "question": "拍手喝采", "answers": [ "はくしゅかっさい" ], "comment": "clapping and cheering; applause" },
  { "question": "拱手傍観", "answers": [ "きょうしゅぼうかん" ], "comment": "stand idly by and watch" },
  { "question": "指差喚呼", "answers": [ "しさかんこ" ], "comment": "pointing and calling (occupational safety method)" },
  { "question": "挙国一致", "answers": [ "きょこくいっち" ], "comment": "national unity" },
  { "question": "挙措進退", "answers": [ "きょそしんたい" ], "comment": "behavior; bearing; demeanor" },
  { "question": "捲土重来", "answers": [ "けんどちょうらい" ], "comment": "recouping one's strength for a renewed attack (on); making another attempt with redoubled efforts" },
  { "question": "換骨奪胎", "answers": [ "かんこつだったい" ], "comment": "adaptation (e.g. of a poem or novel); rewriting; recasting; modification; rehashing" },
  { "question": "揣摩臆測", "answers": [ "しまおくそく" ], "comment": "conjectures and surmises; speculation; giving one's imagination full play without any ground" },
  { "question": "支離滅裂", "answers": [ "しりめつれつ" ], "comment": "incoherent; inconsistent; illogical; disorderly; confused; nonsensical" },
  { "question": "攻城野戦", "answers": [ "こうじょうやせん" ] },
  { "question": "放歌高吟", "answers": [ "ほうかこうぎん" ], "comment": "loud singing" },
  { "question": "放縦不羈", "answers": [ "ほうじゅうふき" ] },
  { "question": "放蕩三昧", "answers": [ "ほうとうざんまい" ], "comment": "being absorbed in self-indulgent pleasures; giving oneself up to debauchery and dissipation" },
  { "question": "放蕩無頼", "answers": [ "ほうとうぶらい" ], "comment": "being dissolute and unruly; ruining oneself by leading a fast life" },
  { "question": "政教一致", "answers": [ "せいきょういっち" ], "comment": "unity of church and state" },
  { "question": "政教分離", "answers": [ "せいきょうぶんり" ], "comment": "separation of church and state" },
  { "question": "故事来歴", "answers": [ "こじらいれき" ], "comment": "origin and history; particulars" },
  { "question": "教唆煽動", "answers": [ "きょうさせんどう" ], "comment": "instigation and abetment" },
  { "question": "教外別伝", "answers": [ "きょうげべつでん" ], "comment": "Buddhist revelation through intuitive discernment; Spiritual awakening cannot be experienced with words and letters; Spiritual enlightenment can be attained only by means of communion of mind with mind (Zen Buddhism)" },
  { "question": "敝衣蓬髪", "answers": [ "へいいほうはつ" ] },
  { "question": "敬天愛人", "answers": [ "けいてんあいじん" ], "comment": "\"Revere heaven, love people.\" (favorite motto of Saigo Takamori, 1827-1877)" },
  { "question": "整理整頓", "answers": [ "せいりせいとん" ], "comment": "keeping things tidy and in order" },
  { "question": "敵前逃亡", "answers": [ "てきぜんとうぼう" ], "comment": "deserting under enemy fire" },
  { "question": "敵本主義", "answers": [ "てきほんしゅぎ" ], "comment": "diversionary tactics; concealing one's true motives until the last moment" },
  { "question": "文人墨客", "answers": [ "ぶんじんぼっかく" ], "comment": "writers and artists; persons who take delight in such refined pursuits as poetry, literature, painting and calligraphy" },
  { "question": "文化遺産", "answers": [ "ぶんかいさん" ], "comment": "cultural heritage" },
  { "question": "文明開化", "answers": [ "ぶんめいかいか" ], "comment": "Japan's Westernization movement during the Meiji era (Westernisation)" },
  { "question": "文武両道", "answers": [ "ぶんぶりょうどう" ], "comment": "(accomplished in) both the literary and military arts" },
  { "question": "文武百官", "answers": [ "ぶんぶひゃっかん" ], "comment": "all the officials, both military and civil" },
  { "question": "文芸復興", "answers": [ "ぶんげいふっこう" ], "comment": "Renaissance" },
  { "question": "斎戒沐浴", "answers": [ "さいかいもくよく" ], "comment": "purification; washing" },
  { "question": "斬新奇抜", "answers": [ "ざんしんきばつ" ], "comment": "novel; unconventional; cutting-edge" },
  { "question": "断崖絶壁", "answers": [ "だんがいぜっぺき" ], "comment": "precipitous cliff; sheer precipice" },
  { "question": "断簡零墨", "answers": [ "だんかんれいぼく" ] },
  { "question": "新進気鋭", "answers": [ "しんしんきえい" ], "comment": "young and energetic; up-and-coming" },
  { "question": "新郎新婦", "answers": [ "しんろうしんぷ" ], "comment": "bride and groom" },
  { "question": "新陳代謝", "answers": [ "しんちんたいしゃ" ], "comment": "renewal; replacement; metabolism" },
  { "question": "旗幟鮮明", "answers": [ "きしせんめい" ], "comment": "making one's attitude (position, stand) clear; unfurling and clearly showing one's banner" },
  { "question": "既成事実", "answers": [ "きせいじじつ" ], "comment": "established fact; fait accompli" },
  { "question": "既成概念", "answers": [ "きせいがいねん" ], "comment": "stereotype; preconceived idea; preconceived notion" },
  { "question": "日常茶飯", "answers": [ "にちじょうさはん" ], "comment": "everyday occurrence" },
  { "question": "日月星辰", "answers": [ "じつげつせいしん" ], "comment": "the sun, the moon and the stars; the heavenly bodies" },
  { "question": "日進月歩", "answers": [ "にっしんげっぽ" ], "comment": "steady progress; rapid advance" },
  { "question": "旧態依然", "answers": [ "きゅうたいいぜん" ], "comment": "remaining unchanged (from the old state of things); none the better for the change (if at all)" },
  { "question": "旭日昇天", "answers": [ "きょくじつしょうてん" ], "comment": "full of vigor and vitality (like the rising sun) (vigour); being in the ascendant" },
  { "question": "明明白白", "answers": [ "めいめいはくはく" ], "comment": "clearly evident; quite obvious; as clear as day; beyond any doubt; strikingly apparent" },
  { "question": "明朗快活", "answers": [ "めいろうかいかつ" ], "comment": "cheerful and openhearted" },
  { "question": "明朗闊達", "answers": [ "めいろうかったつ" ], "comment": "upbeat and freehearted; cheerful and magnanimous" },
  { "question": "明眸皓歯", "answers": [ "めいぼうこうし" ], "comment": "starry eyes and beautiful white teeth (said of beautiful women)" },
  { "question": "明鏡止水", "answers": [ "めいきょうしすい" ], "comment": "clear and serene (as a polished mirror and still water)" },
  { "question": "春夏秋冬", "answers": [ "しゅんかしゅうとう" ], "comment": "spring, summer, autumn (fall) and winter; the four seasons" },
  { "question": "春宵一刻", "answers": [ "しゅんしょういっこく" ], "comment": "a moment of time in a spring evening (is worth a thousand pieces of gold)" },
  { "question": "春風駘蕩", "answers": [ "しゅんぷうたいとう" ], "comment": "warm and genial spring weather; genial and balmy" },
  { "question": "是生滅法", "answers": [ "ぜしょうめっぽう" ], "comment": "the law of arising and ceasing; the law of creation and destruction" },
  { "question": "是非善悪", "answers": [ "ぜひぜんあく" ], "comment": "rights and wrongs; the relative merits (of a case); propriety" },
  { "question": "昼夜兼行", "answers": [ "ちゅうやけんこう" ], "comment": "around-the-clock; (working) day and night" },
  { "question": "時世時節", "answers": [ "ときよじせつ" ], "comment": "times and situations; the course of events of the times; a turn of Fortune's wheel" },
  { "question": "時代錯誤", "answers": [ "じだいさくご" ], "comment": "anachronism" },
  { "question": "時期尚早", "answers": [ "じきしょうそう" ], "comment": "premature" },
  { "question": "時節到来", "answers": [ "じせつとうらい" ], "comment": "The time has come (for, to, when...); The time being ripe (for)" },
  { "question": "晴耕雨読", "answers": [ "せいこううどく" ], "comment": "working in the field in fine weather and reading at home in rainy weather; living in quiet retirement dividing time between work and intellectual pursuits" },
  { "question": "暗中摸索", "answers": [ "あんちゅうもさく" ], "comment": "groping in the dark; exploring new avenues without having any clues" },
  { "question": "暗雲低迷", "answers": [ "あんうんていめい" ], "comment": "gathering dark clouds; being under the shadow of" },
  { "question": "暗黒時代", "answers": [ "あんこくじだい" ], "comment": "Dark Ages\ndark age" },
  { "question": "暮色蒼然", "answers": [ "ぼしょくそうぜん" ], "comment": "dusky; somber light of a gathering dusk" },
  { "question": "暴虎馮河", "answers": [ "ぼうこひょうが" ], "comment": "foolhardy courage" },
  { "question": "暴虐非道", "answers": [ "ぼうぎゃくひどう" ], "comment": "violent and cruel; tyrannical and atrocious" },
  { "question": "暴飲暴食", "answers": [ "ぼういんぼうしょく" ], "comment": "drinking and eating too much" },
  { "question": "曖昧模糊", "answers": [ "あいまいもこ" ], "comment": "obscure; vague; ambiguous" },
  { "question": "曲学阿世", "answers": [ "きょくがくあせい" ], "comment": "prostitution of learning; twisting the truth and truckling to the times" },
  { "question": "曲眉豊頬", "answers": [ "きょくびほうきょう" ] },
  { "question": "書画骨董", "answers": [ "しょがこっとう" ], "comment": "curios and objets d'art" },
  { "question": "最後通牒", "answers": [ "さいごつうちょう" ], "comment": "ultimatum" },
  { "question": "月下氷人", "answers": [ "げっかひょうじん" ], "comment": "go-between; matchmaker; Cupid" },
  { "question": "月下老人", "answers": [ "げっかろうじん" ], "comment": "go-between; matchmaker" },
  { "question": "月卿雲客", "answers": [ "げっけいうんかく" ], "comment": "court nobles and other courtiers allowed into the Imperial Palace" },
  { "question": "月白風清", "answers": [ "げっぱくふうせい" ] },
  { "question": "有名無実", "answers": [ "ゆうめいむじつ" ], "comment": "in name but not in reality" },
  { "question": "有害無益", "answers": [ "ゆうがいむえき" ], "comment": "more harm than good; harmful and of no use" },
  { "question": "有形無形", "answers": [ "ゆうけいむけい" ], "comment": "tangible and intangible; material and spiritual" },
  { "question": "有為転変", "answers": [ "ういてんぺん" ], "comment": "mutability (of worldly affairs); fleeting shifts and changes (of human life)" },
  { "question": "有耶無耶", "answers": [ "うやむや" ], "comment": "indefinite; hazy; vague; unsettled; undecided" },
  { "question": "有職故実", "answers": [ "ゆうそくこじつ" ], "comment": "well-versed in usages or practices of the court or military households" },
  { "question": "有言実行", "answers": [ "ゆうげんじっこう" ], "comment": "carrying out one's words; being as good as one's word; making good on one's promise" },
  { "question": "有象無象", "answers": [ "うぞうむぞう" ], "comment": "mob; the masses; rabble; riffraff" },
  { "question": "朝令暮改", "answers": [ "ちょうれいぼかい" ], "comment": "an unsettled course of action; (orders or laws) being revised often with no guiding principles" },
  { "question": "朝朝暮暮", "answers": [ "ちょうちょうぼぼ" ], "comment": "every morning and evening" },
  { "question": "朝雲暮雨", "answers": [ "ちょううんぼう" ], "comment": "sexual liaison" },
  { "question": "木端微塵", "answers": [ "こっぱみじん" ], "comment": "broken into small fragments; smashed to atoms; fragments and splinters; smithereens" },
  { "question": "未来永劫", "answers": [ "みらいえいごう" ], "comment": "forevermore; for eternity" },
  { "question": "本地垂迹", "answers": [ "ほんちすいじゃく" ] },
  { "question": "本家本元", "answers": [ "ほんけほんもと" ], "comment": "original home; birthplace; originator" },
  { "question": "本末転倒", "answers": [ "ほんまつてんとう" ], "comment": "failing to properly evaluate the (relative) importance (of); putting the cart before the horse; mistaking the cause for the end; mistaking the insignificant for the essential; getting one's priorities backwards" },
  { "question": "本領安堵", "answers": [ "ほんりょうあんど" ], "comment": "recognition and guarantee, by the shogunate, of ownership of the inherited estate of a samurai who pledged allegiance to it (in the Kamakura and early Muromachi periods)" },
  { "question": "杓子定規", "answers": [ "しゃくしじょうぎ" ], "comment": "strict; hidebound; inflexible; being a sticker for the rules; sticking hard and fast to the rules" },
  { "question": "条件反射", "answers": [ "じょうけんはんしゃ" ], "comment": "conditioned reflex" },
  { "question": "杯盤狼藉", "answers": [ "はいばんろうぜき" ], "comment": "glasses and plates being scattered about after a party or banquet; articles lying about in a jumble" },
  { "question": "東奔西走", "answers": [ "とうほんせいそう" ], "comment": "busying oneself about (something); being on the move; bestirring oneself; on the go; taking an active interest" },
  { "question": "東岳大帝", "answers": [ "とうがくたいてい" ] },
  { "question": "東西南北", "answers": [ "とうざいなんぼく" ], "comment": "east, west, south and north" },
  { "question": "東西古今", "answers": [ "とうざいここん" ], "comment": "all times and places; everywhen and everywhere" },
  { "question": "枉尺直尋", "answers": [ "おうせきちょくじん" ] },
  { "question": "枝葉末節", "answers": [ "しようまっせつ" ], "comment": "unimportant details; inessentials" },
  { "question": "枯木寒巌", "answers": [ "こぼくかんがん" ], "comment": "withered trees and frozen rocks; a person that is hard to approach" },
  { "question": "柔能制剛", "answers": [ "じゅうのうせいごう" ] },
  { "question": "柳暗花明", "answers": [ "りゅうあんかめい" ], "comment": "beautiful scenery of spring\nred-light district" },
  { "question": "柳緑花紅", "answers": [ "りゅうりょくかこう" ], "comment": "red blossoms and green willows; beautiful scenery of spring; natural beauty; beauty of nature" },
  { "question": "栄枯盛衰", "answers": [ "えいこせいすい" ], "comment": "ups and downs of life; vicissitudes of fortune" },
  { "question": "栄耀栄華", "answers": [ "えいようえいが" ], "comment": "wealth, prosperity, and arrogant splendor (splendour); (living sumptuously) intoxicated by wealth and power; luxury" },
  { "question": "栄辱得喪", "answers": [ "えいじょくとくそう" ] },
  { "question": "桜花爛漫", "answers": [ "おうからんまん" ], "comment": "riot of cherry blossoms" },
  { "question": "森羅万象", "answers": [ "しんらばんしょう" ], "comment": "all things in nature; the whole creation" },
  { "question": "極悪非道", "answers": [ "ごくあくひどう" ], "comment": "inhuman; heinous; atrocious" },
  { "question": "極楽往生", "answers": [ "ごくらくおうじょう" ], "comment": "rebirth in paradise; peaceful death" },
  { "question": "極楽浄土", "answers": [ "ごくらくじょうど" ], "comment": "Sukhavati (Amitabha's Pure Land)" },
  { "question": "極楽蜻蛉", "answers": [ "ごくらくとんぼ" ], "comment": "happy-go-lucky fellow; an easygoing and indifferent person; a pococurante" },
  { "question": "槿花一朝", "answers": [ "きんかいっちょう" ], "comment": "evanescent glory; passing prosperity" },
  { "question": "権謀術数", "answers": [ "けんぼうじゅっすう" ], "comment": "trickery; wiles; finesse; Machiavellism" },
  { "question": "権謀術策", "answers": [ "けんぼうじゅっさく" ], "comment": "trickery; wiles; intriguing strategy cleverly designed to fool others; Machiavellism" },
  { "question": "横行跋扈", "answers": [ "おうこうばっこ" ], "comment": "being rampant; (evildoers) roaming at will" },
  { "question": "横行闊歩", "answers": [ "おうこうかっぽ" ], "comment": "swaggering" },
  { "question": "樹下石上", "answers": [ "じゅかせきじょう" ] },
  { "question": "機会均等", "answers": [ "きかいきんとう" ], "comment": "equal opportunity" },
  { "question": "機嫌気褄", "answers": [ "きげんきづま" ], "comment": "humour; humor; temper; mood; spirits" },
  { "question": "機略縦横", "answers": [ "きりゃくじゅうおう" ], "comment": "very resourcefully using tactics adapting oneself to the requirements of the moment; playing it by ear; acting according to circumstances" },
  { "question": "欠席裁判", "answers": [ "けっせきさいばん" ], "comment": "trial in absentia; judgment by default (judgement)" },
  { "question": "欣喜雀躍", "answers": [ "きんきじゃくやく" ], "comment": "jump up for joy" },
  { "question": "欣求浄土", "answers": [ "ごんぐじょうど" ], "comment": "seeking rebirth in the Pure Land" },
  { "question": "歌舞音曲", "answers": [ "かぶおんきょく" ], "comment": "public music and dancing; performance of song and dance entertainment" },
  { "question": "歓天喜地", "answers": [ "かんてんきち" ], "comment": "great joy; jubilation; exultation" },
  { "question": "歓言愉色", "answers": [ "かんげんゆしょく" ] },
  { "question": "正当防衛", "answers": [ "せいとうぼうえい" ], "comment": "legitimate self-defence; legitimate self-defense" },
  { "question": "正正堂堂", "answers": [ "せいせいどうどう" ], "comment": "fair and square; open and aboveboard" },
  { "question": "正真正銘", "answers": [ "しょうしんしょうめい" ], "comment": "genuine; authentic" },
  { "question": "正邪曲直", "answers": [ "せいじゃきょくちょく" ], "comment": "right and (or) wrong" },
  { "question": "武者修行", "answers": [ "むしゃしゅぎょう" ], "comment": "traveling about to gain skill in combat (travelling)" },
  { "question": "武芸百般", "answers": [ "ぶげいひゃっぱん" ], "comment": "every martial art; all the martial arts" },
  { "question": "武運長久", "answers": [ "ぶうんちょうきゅう" ], "comment": "continued luck in the fortunes of war" },
  { "question": "武陵桃源", "answers": [ "ぶりょうとうげん" ], "comment": "Utopia" },
  { "question": "武骨一辺", "answers": [ "ぶこついっぺん" ] },
  { "question": "歳歳年年", "answers": [ "さいさいねんねん" ], "comment": "annually; every year; year in and year out; from year to year" },
  { "question": "残忍酷薄", "answers": [ "ざんにんこくはく" ], "comment": "cruel; brutal; atrocious; merciless" },
  { "question": "残念無念", "answers": [ "ざんねんむねん" ], "comment": "deep regret; bitter disappointment; chagrin; vexation" },
  { "question": "残念至極", "answers": [ "ざんねんしごく" ], "comment": "deep regret; bitter disappointment; chagrin; vexation" },
  { "question": "殺生禁断", "answers": [ "せっしょうきんだん" ], "comment": "prohibition against hunting and fishing" },
  { "question": "毀誉褒貶", "answers": [ "きよほうへん" ], "comment": "praise and censure; public criticisms" },
  { "question": "比翼連理", "answers": [ "ひよくれんり" ], "comment": "marital vows" },
  { "question": "気宇壮大", "answers": [ "きうそうだい" ], "comment": "magnanimous in one's attitude of mind; grand in one's idea or mind-set" },
  { "question": "気宇広大", "answers": [ "きうこうだい" ], "comment": "magnanimous" },
  { "question": "気息奄々", "answers": [ "きそくえんえん" ], "comment": "gasping for breath; at one's last gasp; breathing feebly; on the brink of death; more dead than alive" },
  { "question": "気炎万丈", "answers": [ "きえんばんじょう" ], "comment": "in high spirits; talking big" },
  { "question": "気韻生動", "answers": [ "きいんせいどう" ], "comment": "being animated (vivid) with grace (elegance, refinement)" },
  { "question": "水平思考", "answers": [ "すいへいしこう" ], "comment": "lateral thinking" },
  { "question": "水村山郭", "answers": [ "すいそんさんかく" ] },
  { "question": "永世中立", "answers": [ "えいせいちゅうりつ" ], "comment": "permanent neutrality" },
  { "question": "永久不変", "answers": [ "えいきゅうふへん" ], "comment": "permanence; forever unchanging" },
  { "question": "永代供養", "answers": [ "えいたいくよう" ], "comment": "services performed in perpetuity by a Buddhist temple for the repose of a departed soul" },
  { "question": "永劫不変", "answers": [ "えいごうふへん" ] },
  { "question": "永劫回帰", "answers": [ "えいごうかいき" ], "comment": "eternal recurrence; eternal return" },
  { "question": "永字八法", "answers": [ "えいじはっぽう" ], "comment": "the eight basic brush strokes in writing Chinese characters" },
  { "question": "永遠不変", "answers": [ "えいえんふへん" ] },
  { "question": "永遠不滅", "answers": [ "えいえんふめつ" ] },
  { "question": "求不得苦", "answers": [ "ぐふとくく" ], "comment": "the pain of not getting what one seeks" },
  { "question": "汗牛充棟", "answers": [ "かんぎゅうじゅうとう" ], "comment": "(having, there being) a great number of books" },
  { "question": "汚名返上", "answers": [ "おめいへんじょう" ], "comment": "clear one's name; redeem oneself; clear (vindicate) one's honor (reputation)" },
  { "question": "沈思黙考", "answers": [ "ちんしもっこう" ], "comment": "being lost in deep thought" },
  { "question": "沈着冷静", "answers": [ "ちんちゃくれいせい" ], "comment": "calm, cool, and collected; level and calm" },
  { "question": "沈魚落雁", "answers": [ "ちんぎょらくがん" ], "comment": "charms of a uniquely beautiful woman; (so beautiful that) fish stay on the bottom of water and flying wild geese fall from the sky in shame" },
  { "question": "沙羅双樹", "answers": [ "さらそうじゅ" ], "comment": "sal (tree) (Shorea robusta); saul\nJapanese stewartia (Stewartia pseudocamellia)" },
  { "question": "没分暁漢", "answers": [ "ぼつぶんぎょうかん" ], "comment": "obstinate person; blockhead" },
  { "question": "没風流漢", "answers": [ "ぼつふうりゅうかん" ], "comment": "prosaic person; person of an unromantic turn of mind; philistine" },
  { "question": "油断大敵", "answers": [ "ゆだんたいてき" ], "comment": "Unpreparedness is one's greatest enemy; He that is too secure is not safe" },
  { "question": "治乱興亡", "answers": [ "ちらんこうぼう" ], "comment": "nation's times of peace and war, rise and fall" },
  { "question": "治外法権", "answers": [ "ちがいほうけん" ], "comment": "extraterritoriality" },
  { "question": "波及効果", "answers": [ "はきゅうこうか" ], "comment": "ripple effect; spillover effect; propagation effect" },
  { "question": "波濤万里", "answers": [ "はとうばんり" ], "comment": "faraway lands; voyage to faraway lands" },
  { "question": "波瀾万丈", "answers": [ "はらんばんじょう" ], "comment": "stormy and full of drama; many drastic events in the course of events; full of ups and downs; with many vicissitudes" },
  { "question": "泰山府君", "answers": [ "たいざんふくん" ] },
  { "question": "泰然自若", "answers": [ "たいぜんじじゃく" ], "comment": "having presence of mind; self-possessed; imperturbable; calm and self-possessed" },
  { "question": "洒掃薪水", "answers": [ "さいそうしんすい" ] },
  { "question": "津津浦浦", "answers": [ "つつうらうら" ], "comment": "all over the country; throughout the land; every nook and cranny of the land" },
  { "question": "活殺自在", "answers": [ "かっさつじざい" ], "comment": "the power of life or death" },
  { "question": "流星光底", "answers": [ "りゅうせいこうてい" ] },
  { "question": "流汗淋漓", "answers": [ "りゅうかんりんり" ], "comment": "profuse perspiration; dripping with sweat" },
  { "question": "流言蜚語", "answers": [ "りゅうげんひご" ], "comment": "false (wild, groundless) rumor (rumour); canard" },
  { "question": "流転輪廻", "answers": [ "るてんりんね" ], "comment": "all things being in flux through the endless circle of birth, death, and rebirth; the circle of transmigration" },
  { "question": "流連荒亡", "answers": [ "りゅうれんこうぼう" ], "comment": "spending all one's time in idle amusement away from home; being absorbed in self-indulgent pleasures" },
  { "question": "浅学非才", "answers": [ "せんがくひさい" ], "comment": "one's lack of learning or ability; shallow learning and limited ability" },
  { "question": "海千山千", "answers": [ "うみせんやません" ], "comment": "sly old dog; old fox" },
  { "question": "涅槃寂静", "answers": [ "ねはんじゃくじょう" ], "comment": "enlightenment leads to serenity" },
  { "question": "消化不良", "answers": [ "しょうかふりょう" ], "comment": "indigestion; dyspepsia" },
  { "question": "淫祠邪教", "answers": [ "いんしじゃきょう" ], "comment": "evil heresies" },
  { "question": "深層心理", "answers": [ "しんそうしんり" ], "comment": "deep psyche; unconscious mind; depth psychology" },
  { "question": "深山幽谷", "answers": [ "しんざんゆうこく" ], "comment": "deep mountain valleys" },
  { "question": "深慮遠謀", "answers": [ "しんりょえんぼう" ], "comment": "deep design and forethought; a farsighted and deeply-laid plan" },
  { "question": "深謀遠慮", "answers": [ "しんぼうえんりょ" ], "comment": "far sight and deep design" },
  { "question": "清廉潔白", "answers": [ "せいれんけっぱく" ], "comment": "being upright and cleanhanded" },
  { "question": "清浄潔白", "answers": [ "しょうじょうけっぱく" ], "comment": "upright and clean-handed; pure in heart and with a clean conscience" },
  { "question": "清浄無垢", "answers": [ "せいじょうむく" ], "comment": "purity; spotlessness" },
  { "question": "清窓浄机", "answers": [ "せいそうじょうき" ] },
  { "question": "温厚篤実", "answers": [ "おんこうとくじつ" ], "comment": "having a gentle and sincere personality" },
  { "question": "温故知新", "answers": [ "おんこちしん" ], "comment": "developing new ideas based on study of the past; learning from the past" },
  { "question": "温良篤厚", "answers": [ "おんりょうとっこう" ] },
  { "question": "渾渾沌沌", "answers": [ "こんこんとんとん" ] },
  { "question": "渾然一体", "answers": [ "こんぜんいったい" ], "comment": "in complete harmony" },
  { "question": "満場一致", "answers": [ "まんじょういっち" ], "comment": "unanimity" },
  { "question": "満目荒涼", "answers": [ "まんもくこうりょう" ], "comment": "all nature being bleak and desolate; scene looking desolate and forlorn as far as the eye can see" },
  { "question": "満身創痍", "answers": [ "まんしんそうい" ], "comment": "having wounds all over one's body" },
  { "question": "溌墨淋漓", "answers": [ "はつぼくりんり" ] },
  { "question": "滅私奉公", "answers": [ "めっしほうこう" ], "comment": "selfless devotion" },
  { "question": "潜在意識", "answers": [ "せんざいいしき" ], "comment": "subconscious (awareness)" },
  { "question": "澆季溷濁", "answers": [ "ぎょうきこんだく" ] },
  { "question": "瀟湘八景", "answers": [ "しょうしょうはっけい" ] },
  { "question": "灼然炳乎", "answers": [ "しゃくぜんへいこ" ] },
  { "question": "炊金饌玉", "answers": [ "すいきんせんぎょく" ] },
  { "question": "無上菩提", "answers": [ "むじょうぼだい" ] },
  { "question": "無上趣味", "answers": [ "むじょうしゅみ" ] },
  { "question": "無事安穏", "answers": [ "ぶじあんのん" ] },
  { "question": "無事平穏", "answers": [ "ぶじへいおん" ], "comment": "peace and quiet; safe and peaceful; tranquil and uneventful" },
  { "question": "無事息災", "answers": [ "ぶじそくさい" ], "comment": "safe and healthy; health and longevity" },
  { "question": "無二無三", "answers": [ "むにむさん" ], "comment": "in earnest; single-minded; with intense concentration; rushing headlong into\none and only; unique" },
  { "question": "無位無冠", "answers": [ "むいむかん" ], "comment": "(a plain citizen) having no special rank or title; being a common citizen" },
  { "question": "無位無官", "answers": [ "むいむかん" ], "comment": "(an ordinary citizen) having no special rank or title" },
  { "question": "無味乾燥", "answers": [ "むみかんそう" ], "comment": "dull and uninteresting; cut-and-dried" },
  { "question": "無始無終", "answers": [ "むしむじゅう" ], "comment": "everlastingness; eternity" },
  { "question": "無学文盲", "answers": [ "むがくもんもう" ], "comment": "ignorant and illiterate; uneducated and illiterate; uneducated and illiterate person" },
  { "question": "無常迅速", "answers": [ "むじょうじんそく" ], "comment": "the (fast) pace at which life passes, and thus the nearness of death; promptitude of the changes of the times" },
  { "question": "無念残念", "answers": [ "むねんざんねん" ] },
  { "question": "無念無想", "answers": [ "むねんむそう" ], "comment": "free from worldly or worthless thoughts" },
  { "question": "無我夢中", "answers": [ "むがむちゅう" ], "comment": "being absorbed in; losing oneself in" },
  { "question": "無手勝流", "answers": [ "むてかつりゅう" ], "comment": "winning without fighting; method used to win without fighting\none's own way of doing things (i.e. as different from that of one's instructor)\nShinto-ryu (school of kenjutsu)" },
  { "question": "無明長夜", "answers": [ "むみょうじょうや" ], "comment": "the long night of spiritual darkness" },
  { "question": "無欲恬淡", "answers": [ "むよくてんたん" ], "comment": "indifferent to worldly gain" },
  { "question": "無為徒食", "answers": [ "むいとしょく" ], "comment": "idling one's time away" },
  { "question": "無為無策", "answers": [ "むいむさく" ], "comment": "do-nothing, plan-nothing (government, etc.)" },
  { "question": "無為無能", "answers": [ "むいむのう" ], "comment": "idle and incompetent; accomplishing nothing significant nor being capable of doing so; lacking the talent to do anything but idle away one's time" },
  { "question": "無理往生", "answers": [ "むりおうじょう" ], "comment": "forced compliance; coercion; compulsion" },
  { "question": "無理無体", "answers": [ "むりむたい" ], "comment": "by force" },
  { "question": "無理算段", "answers": [ "むりさんだん" ], "comment": "scraping together (a sum of money); raising (a sum of money) by straining one's credit" },
  { "question": "無理難題", "answers": [ "むりなんだい" ], "comment": "unreasonable demand" },
  { "question": "無理非道", "answers": [ "むりひどう" ], "comment": "unreasonable and unjust; unconscionable" },
  { "question": "無病息災", "answers": [ "むびょうそくさい" ], "comment": "sound health" },
  { "question": "無知蒙昧", "answers": [ "むちもうまい" ], "comment": "unenlightened; in the darkest ignorance" },
  { "question": "無礼傲慢", "answers": [ "ぶれいごうまん" ] },
  { "question": "無礼千万", "answers": [ "ぶれいせんばん" ], "comment": "extremely rude (impertinent, impolite)" },
  { "question": "無縫天衣", "answers": [ "むほうてんい" ] },
  { "question": "無罪放免", "answers": [ "むざいほうめん" ], "comment": "acquittal" },
  { "question": "無芸大食", "answers": [ "むげいたいしょく" ], "comment": "lacking the talent to do anything but eat" },
  { "question": "無茶苦茶", "answers": [ "むちゃくちゃ" ], "comment": "nonsensical; unreasonable; absurd; unrealistic\nawfully; extremely; to excess; senseless; reckless\ndisorder; confusion; being jumbled; being mixed up\nvery; extremely; excessively" },
  { "question": "無間地獄", "answers": [ "むけんじごく" ], "comment": "the Avici hell, the eighth and most painful of the eight hells in Buddhism; Buddhist hell of uninterrupted suffering" },
  { "question": "焦熱地獄", "answers": [ "しょうねつじごく" ], "comment": "burning hell; inferno" },
  { "question": "煩悶懊悩", "answers": [ "はんもんおうのう" ], "comment": "anguish; agony" },
  { "question": "熟読玩味", "answers": [ "じゅくどくがんみ" ], "comment": "reading carefully with appreciation; giving (something) a careful perusal" },
  { "question": "父子相伝", "answers": [ "ふしそうでん" ], "comment": "transmission of the secrets of an art, craft, trade or learning from father to son" },
  { "question": "父祖伝来", "answers": [ "ふそでんらい" ], "comment": "hereditary; patrimonial; handed down from generation to generation" },
  { "question": "片言隻句", "answers": [ "へんげんせきく" ], "comment": "few words; single phrase" },
  { "question": "片言隻語", "answers": [ "へんげんせきご" ], "comment": "(not even) a few words" },
  { "question": "版籍奉還", "answers": [ "はんせきほうかん" ], "comment": "the return of the land and people from the feudal lords to the Emperor" },
  { "question": "牛歩戦術", "answers": [ "ぎゅうほせんじゅつ" ], "comment": "snail's pace tactics; walking slowly when voting in the Diet to delay proceedings" },
  { "question": "牛頭馬頭", "answers": [ "ごずめず" ], "comment": "horse-headed and ox-headed demons in the Buddhist hell" },
  { "question": "牛鬼蛇神", "answers": [ "ぎゅうきだしん" ], "comment": "wicked and perverse; weird and incoherent" },
  { "question": "物情騒然", "answers": [ "ぶつじょうそうぜん" ], "comment": "unrest prevailing; turmoil reigning" },
  { "question": "物我一体", "answers": [ "もつがいったい" ] },
  { "question": "物見遊山", "answers": [ "ものみゆさん" ], "comment": "going on a pleasure jaunt" },
  { "question": "特筆大書", "answers": [ "とくひつたいしょ" ], "comment": "(printed or written in) large letters" },
  { "question": "牽強付会", "answers": [ "けんきょうふかい" ], "comment": "farfetched (argument, opinion); forced (sense, view); strained (interpretation); distorted" },
  { "question": "狂喜乱舞", "answers": [ "きょうきらんぶ" ], "comment": "boisterous dance; dancing wildly" },
  { "question": "狂瀾怒濤", "answers": [ "きょうらんどとう" ] },
  { "question": "狂言綺語", "answers": [ "きょうげんきご" ], "comment": "make-believe fiction" },
  { "question": "狐狸妖怪", "answers": [ "こりようかい" ], "comment": "tricksters; deceivers; fey creatures; monsters; goblins" },
  { "question": "狐疑逡巡", "answers": [ "こぎしゅんじゅん" ], "comment": "being in doubt and unable to decide; hesitation and indecision" },
  { "question": "独断専行", "answers": [ "どくだんせんこう" ], "comment": "acting arbitrarily on one's own authority; acting arbitrarily without consultation" },
  { "question": "独立不羈", "answers": [ "どくりつふき" ], "comment": "acting according to one's own beliefs, being undisturbed by others" },
  { "question": "独立独歩", "answers": [ "どくりつどっぽ" ], "comment": "self-reliance; self-help" },
  { "question": "独立自尊", "answers": [ "どくりつじそん" ], "comment": "(spirit of) independence and self-respect" },
  { "question": "猪突猛進", "answers": [ "ちょとつもうしん" ], "comment": "headlong; foolhardy; reckless" },
  { "question": "獅子奮迅", "answers": [ "ししふんじん" ], "comment": "being irresistible; being furiously vigorous; being intensely forceful" },
  { "question": "獅子身中", "answers": [ "しししんちゅう" ], "comment": "treacherous friend; snake in one's bosom; treacherous insider" },
  { "question": "率先垂範", "answers": [ "そっせんすいはん" ], "comment": "set an example worth following; take the initiative in doing something thereby setting an example for others to follow" },
  { "question": "玉石混淆", "answers": [ "ぎょくせきこんこう" ], "comment": "mixture of wheat and chaff; mixture of the good and bad; jumble of wheat and tares" },
  { "question": "王政復古", "answers": [ "おうせいふっこ" ], "comment": "restoration of imperial rule; (in English history) the Restoration" },
  { "question": "王道楽土", "answers": [ "おうどうらくど" ], "comment": "Arcadia, presided over by a virtuous king" },
  { "question": "珍味佳肴", "answers": [ "ちんみかこう" ], "comment": "rare delicacies; rare treat" },
  { "question": "現世利益", "answers": [ "げんぜりやく" ], "comment": "benefits gained in this world through observance of the Buddhist teachings; happiness gained in this world through observance of the Buddhist teachings" },
  { "question": "現状打破", "answers": [ "げんじょうだは" ], "comment": "abandonment of the status quo; destroying the status quo; overthrowing the present situation" },
  { "question": "現状維持", "answers": [ "げんじょういじ" ], "comment": "maintenance of the status quo" },
  { "question": "理路整然", "answers": [ "りろせいぜん" ], "comment": "logical; cogent; well-reasoned" },
  { "question": "理非曲直", "answers": [ "りひきょくちょく" ], "comment": "the rights and wrongs (of a case)" },
  { "question": "琴瑟相和", "answers": [ "きんしつそうわ" ], "comment": "pair of persons (especially a married couple) being intimate and harmonious; being happily married" },
  { "question": "琴瑟調和", "answers": [ "きんしつちょうわ" ] },
  { "question": "生々流転", "answers": [ "せいせいるてん" ], "comment": "all things being in flux through the endless circle of birth, death, and rebirth; the circle of transmigration" },
  { "question": "生存競争", "answers": [ "せいぞんきょうそう" ], "comment": "struggle for existence" },
  { "question": "生死事大", "answers": [ "しょうじじだい" ] },
  { "question": "生死流転", "answers": [ "しょうじるてん" ], "comment": "all things being in flux through the endless circle of birth, death, and rebirth; the circle of transmigration" },
  { "question": "生殺与奪", "answers": [ "せいさつよだつ" ], "comment": "(having) life-and-death power (over)" },
  { "question": "生滅滅已", "answers": [ "しょうめつめつい" ], "comment": "going beyond life and death and entering Nirvana" },
  { "question": "生生世世", "answers": [ "しょうじょうせぜ" ], "comment": "eternity; forever; through all eternity" },
  { "question": "生老病死", "answers": [ "しょうろうびょうし" ], "comment": "the four inevitables in human life (birth, aging, sickness, and death)" },
  { "question": "生者必滅", "answers": [ "しょうじゃひつめつ" ], "comment": "All living things must die" },
  { "question": "産学協同", "answers": [ "さんがくきょうどう" ], "comment": "industry-university cooperation" },
  { "question": "用意万端", "answers": [ "よういばんたん" ], "comment": "every preparation possible; all aspects of the preparation" },
  { "question": "用意周到", "answers": [ "よういしゅうとう" ], "comment": "very careful; thoroughly prepared" },
  { "question": "田夫野人", "answers": [ "でんぷやじん" ], "comment": "rustic; boor; hick" },
  { "question": "甲論乙駁", "answers": [ "こうろんおつばく" ], "comment": "arguments pro and con" },
  { "question": "男尊女卑", "answers": [ "だんそんじょひ" ], "comment": "male domination of women; male chauvinism; subjection of women" },
  { "question": "画竜点睛", "answers": [ "がりょうてんせい" ], "comment": "finishing touch; completing (something) by executing the final, critical step" },
  { "question": "異体同心", "answers": [ "いたいどうしん" ], "comment": "being of one mind; acting in one accord; behaving in perfect harmony" },
  { "question": "異口同音", "answers": [ "いくどうおん" ], "comment": "in concert; with one voice; unanimously" },
  { "question": "異国情緒", "answers": [ "いこくじょうちょ" ], "comment": "exotic mood; exotic atmosphere; exoticism" },
  { "question": "異類異形", "answers": [ "いるいいぎょう" ], "comment": "strange-looking creatures; spirits and goblins" },
  { "question": "疑心暗鬼", "answers": [ "ぎしんあんき" ], "comment": "Suspicion will raise bogies; Once you suspect something, everything else will look suspicious; Jumping at shadows" },
  { "question": "疲労困憊", "answers": [ "ひろうこんぱい" ], "comment": "total exhaustion" },
  { "question": "疾風怒濤", "answers": [ "しっぷうどとう" ], "comment": "storm and stress; Sturm und Drang" },
  { "question": "疾風迅雷", "answers": [ "しっぷうじんらい" ], "comment": "with lightning speed" },
  { "question": "痛快無比", "answers": [ "つうかいむひ" ], "comment": "very thrilling; extremely delightful; awfully pleasant; intensely satisfying" },
  { "question": "痛烈無比", "answers": [ "つうれつむひ" ] },
  { "question": "痩身矮躯", "answers": [ "そうしんわいく" ] },
  { "question": "痩身長躯", "answers": [ "そうしんちょうく" ] },
  { "question": "痩躯長身", "answers": [ "そうくちょうしん" ] },
  { "question": "発菩提心", "answers": [ "ほつぼだいしん" ], "comment": "deciding to embrace Buddhism; deciding to seek enlightenment; seeking to have religious awakening" },
  { "question": "白河夜船", "answers": [ "しらかわよふね" ], "comment": "being fast asleep (and totally unaware of what is going on around one)\nknow-it-all manner" },
  { "question": "白玉楼中", "answers": [ "はくぎょくろうちゅう" ] },
  { "question": "白砂青松", "answers": [ "はくしゃせいしょう" ], "comment": "white sand and green pines; beautiful stretch of sandy beach dotted with pine trees" },
  { "question": "白紙委任", "answers": [ "はくしいにん" ], "comment": "carte blanche; blank check; blank cheque; unconditional authority" },
  { "question": "白紙撤回", "answers": [ "はくしてっかい" ], "comment": "complete revocation; total retraction" },
  { "question": "百人百様", "answers": [ "ひゃくにんひゃくよう" ], "comment": "so many men, so many ways; to each one's own; it takes all sorts to make a world" },
  { "question": "百八煩悩", "answers": [ "ひゃくはちぼんのう" ], "comment": "the 108 kleshas; the 108 afflictions" },
  { "question": "百姓一揆", "answers": [ "ひゃくしょういっき" ], "comment": "peasant's revolt" },
  { "question": "百家争鳴", "answers": [ "ひゃっかそうめい" ], "comment": "Let a hundred schools of thought contend" },
  { "question": "百尺竿頭", "answers": [ "ひゃくせきかんとう" ], "comment": "the highest state of one's enlightenment; the highest level one can attain" },
  { "question": "百川学海", "answers": [ "ひゃくせんがっかい" ] },
  { "question": "百年河清", "answers": [ "ひゃくねんかせい" ], "comment": "waiting for one hundred years for the waters of the Yellow River to clear; waiting in vain for an unlikely event; waiting for pigs to fly; When the sky falls, we shall catch larks" },
  { "question": "百戦百勝", "answers": [ "ひゃくせんひゃくしょう" ], "comment": "ever-victorious; many successful campaigns; invincibility" },
  { "question": "百戦錬磨", "answers": [ "ひゃくせんれんま" ], "comment": "veteran; (someone) schooled by adversity in many battles; (someone) rich in life's experience gained through much adversity" },
  { "question": "百折不撓", "answers": [ "ひゃくせつふとう" ], "comment": "indefatigability; indomitableness" },
  { "question": "百発百中", "answers": [ "ひゃっぱつひゃくちゅう" ], "comment": "always hitting the bull's-eye; infallible" },
  { "question": "百花繚乱", "answers": [ "ひゃっかりょうらん" ], "comment": "many flowers blooming in profusion; a gathering of many beautiful women (talented people); simultaneous emergence of many talents and achievements" },
  { "question": "百鬼夜行", "answers": [ "ひゃっきやこう" ], "comment": "many monsters, spirits, etc. forming a line and walking through the night\nveritable pandemonium; large number of people plotting and doing evil; creepy characters roaming about presenting a most scandalous sight" },
  { "question": "皮相浅薄", "answers": [ "ひそうせんぱく" ], "comment": "shallow and unwise; superficial and thoughtless" },
  { "question": "盂蘭盆会", "answers": [ "うらぼんえ" ], "comment": "Bon festival; Feast of Lanterns; Buddhist ceremony held on July 15; ullambana" },
  { "question": "盗人根性", "answers": [ "ぬすびとこんじょう" ], "comment": "thievish nature (character); thieving heart; cunning and greedy character" },
  { "question": "盛者必衰", "answers": [ "じょうしゃひっすい" ], "comment": "Even the prosperous inevitably decay (from the Humane King Sutra); sic transit gloria mundi" },
  { "question": "目茶目茶", "answers": [ "めちゃめちゃ" ], "comment": "disorderly; messy; ruined\nabsurd; unreasonable; excessive; rash\nvery; extremely" },
  { "question": "直情径行", "answers": [ "ちょくじょうけいこう" ], "comment": "impulsive and straightforward; guileless" },
  { "question": "直指人心", "answers": [ "じきしにんしん" ] },
  { "question": "直立不動", "answers": [ "ちょくりつふどう" ], "comment": "standing at attention" },
  { "question": "相乗効果", "answers": [ "そうじょうこうか" ], "comment": "synergy" },
  { "question": "相互扶助", "answers": [ "そうごふじょ" ], "comment": "mutual aid" },
  { "question": "相即不離", "answers": [ "そうそくふり" ], "comment": "strongly attached to each other; inseparable" },
  { "question": "相思相愛", "answers": [ "そうしそうあい" ], "comment": "mutual love" },
  { "question": "相関関係", "answers": [ "そうかんかんけい" ], "comment": "correlation; interrelation; intertwining" },
  { "question": "眉目秀麗", "answers": [ "びもくしゅうれい" ], "comment": "handsome" },
  { "question": "真一文字", "answers": [ "まいちもんじ" ], "comment": "straight; as the crow flies" },
  { "question": "真剣勝負", "answers": [ "しんけんしょうぶ" ], "comment": "fighting with real swords; game played in real earnest" },
  { "question": "真実一路", "answers": [ "しんじついちろ" ], "comment": "path of sincerity" },
  { "question": "真相究明", "answers": [ "しんそうきゅうめい" ], "comment": "probe into the truth (of the matter); dig into the real facts of the case; get at the root of a matter" },
  { "question": "眺望絶佳", "answers": [ "ちょうぼうぜっか" ] },
  { "question": "眼光炯炯", "answers": [ "がんこうけいけい" ], "comment": "having piercing eyes; eagle-eyed; having a penetrating insight (into)" },
  { "question": "眼光紙背", "answers": [ "がんこうしはい" ], "comment": "reading between the lines" },
  { "question": "眼高手低", "answers": [ "がんこうしゅてい" ], "comment": "able to criticize but not to create (criticise)" },
  { "question": "矛盾撞着", "answers": [ "むじゅんどうちゃく" ], "comment": "self-contradiction" },
  { "question": "知勇兼備", "answers": [ "ちゆうけんび" ], "comment": "having both wisdom and courage" },
  { "question": "知己朋友", "answers": [ "ちきほうゆう" ], "comment": "intimate friends and acquaintances" },
  { "question": "石破天驚", "answers": [ "せきはてんきょう" ] },
  { "question": "石部金吉", "answers": [ "いしべきんきち" ], "comment": "man of incorruptible character" },
  { "question": "砂上楼閣", "answers": [ "さじょうのろうかく" ] },
  { "question": "砲煙弾雨", "answers": [ "ほうえんだんう" ], "comment": "the smoke of guns and a rain of bullets or shells" },
  { "question": "破邪顕正", "answers": [ "はじゃけんしょう" ], "comment": "(sense of) crushing evil and spreading the truth" },
  { "question": "破顔一笑", "answers": [ "はがんいっしょう" ], "comment": "smiling broadly" },
  { "question": "確乎不抜", "answers": [ "かっこふばつ" ], "comment": "determined; steadfast; unswerving; unshakable" },
  { "question": "社交辞令", "answers": [ "しゃこうじれい" ], "comment": "polite or diplomatic way of putting things; honeyed words; lip service" },
  { "question": "祇園精舎", "answers": [ "ぎおんしょうじゃ" ] },
  { "question": "祖先伝来", "answers": [ "そせんでんらい" ], "comment": "hereditary" },
  { "question": "祖先崇拝", "answers": [ "そせんすうはい" ], "comment": "ancestor worship" },
  { "question": "神仏混淆", "answers": [ "しんぶつこんこう" ], "comment": "mixture (synthesis) of Buddhism and Shintoism" },
  { "question": "神仙思想", "answers": [ "しんせんしそう" ], "comment": "Shenxian thought (ancient Chinese folk belief in the existence of mountain wizards)" },
  { "question": "神出鬼没", "answers": [ "しんしゅつきぼつ" ], "comment": "appearing in unexpected places and at unexpected moments; elusive; phantom" },
  { "question": "神算鬼謀", "answers": [ "しんさんきぼう" ], "comment": "inscrutable stratagem; ingenious scheme" },
  { "question": "神経衰弱", "answers": [ "しんけいすいじゃく" ], "comment": "neurasthenia; nervous breakdown\nconcentration (card game involving turning over face-down cards to find identical pairs)" },
  { "question": "神色自若", "answers": [ "しんしょくじじゃく" ], "comment": "perfect composure; calm and collected" },
  { "question": "神韻縹渺", "answers": [ "しんいんひょうびょう" ], "comment": "(a work of art being) sublime; transcendent" },
  { "question": "祥月命日", "answers": [ "しょうつきめいにち" ], "comment": "anniversary of a person's death" },
  { "question": "祭政一致", "answers": [ "さいせいいっち" ], "comment": "unity of church and state; theocracy" },
  { "question": "福徳円満", "answers": [ "ふくとくえんまん" ], "comment": "being perfectly happy and prosperous; wealth and happiness" },
  { "question": "私利私欲", "answers": [ "しりしよく" ], "comment": "desire to act only in one's self-interest; selfish desires" },
  { "question": "秋霜烈日", "answers": [ "しゅうそうれつじつ" ], "comment": "harshness; severity" },
  { "question": "稲麻竹葦", "answers": [ "とうまちくい" ] },
  { "question": "空中分解", "answers": [ "くうちゅうぶんかい" ], "comment": "mid-air breakage or disintegration" },
  { "question": "空中楼閣", "answers": [ "くうちゅうのろうかく" ], "comment": "castle in the air" },
  { "question": "空前絶後", "answers": [ "くうぜんぜつご" ], "comment": "(so marvelous or horrible that it may be) the first and probably the last" },
  { "question": "空即是色", "answers": [ "くうそくぜしき" ], "comment": "emptiness is form; illusion of the reality of matter" },
  { "question": "空山一路", "answers": [ "くうざんいちろ" ] },
  { "question": "空理空論", "answers": [ "くうりくうろん" ], "comment": "impractical or useless theory" },
  { "question": "空空寂寂", "answers": [ "くうくうじゃくじゃく" ], "comment": "deserted and lonesome; quiet and alone; innocent and nonattached; All is void" },
  { "question": "空花乱墜", "answers": [ "くうげらんつい" ] },
  { "question": "立居振舞", "answers": [ "たちいふるまい" ], "comment": "movements; behavior; behaviour; bearing; deportment; manners; demeanor" },
  { "question": "立身出世", "answers": [ "りっしんしゅっせ" ], "comment": "success in life" },
  { "question": "竜女成仏", "answers": [ "りゅうにょじょうぶつ" ] },
  { "question": "竜華三会", "answers": [ "りゅうげさんね" ] },
  { "question": "竜虎相搏", "answers": [ "りゅうこそうはく" ] },
  { "question": "竜頭蛇尾", "answers": [ "りゅうとうだび" ], "comment": "a strong beginning and a weak ending; an anticlimax" },
  { "question": "竜騰虎闘", "answers": [ "りょうとうことう" ] },
  { "question": "笑止千万", "answers": [ "しょうしせんばん" ], "comment": "highly ridiculous; quite absurd" },
  { "question": "篤実温厚", "answers": [ "とくじつおんこう" ] },
  { "question": "簡単明瞭", "answers": [ "かんたんめいりょう" ], "comment": "simple and clear" },
  { "question": "簡潔明瞭", "answers": [ "かんけつめいりょう" ], "comment": "clear and concise" },
  { "question": "粉飾決算", "answers": [ "ふんしょくけっさん" ], "comment": "fraudulent accounting; window-dressing settlement of accounts; creative accounting" },
  { "question": "粉骨砕身", "answers": [ "ふんこつさいしん" ], "comment": "making one's best exertions" },
  { "question": "粗衣粗食", "answers": [ "そいそしょく" ], "comment": "simple life; frugal life" },
  { "question": "粗製濫造", "answers": [ "そせいらんぞう" ], "comment": "mass production of inferior goods" },
  { "question": "粟散辺地", "answers": [ "ぞくさんへんち" ] },
  { "question": "精力絶倫", "answers": [ "せいりょくぜつりん" ], "comment": "being of unbounded energy; being with matchless vigor; having endless sexual stamina" },
  { "question": "精励恪勤", "answers": [ "せいれいかっきん" ], "comment": "assiduousness; attending diligently to one's study or duties" },
  { "question": "精神一到", "answers": [ "せいしんいっとう" ], "comment": "concentration of mind; mental concentration (on some task)" },
  { "question": "精神統一", "answers": [ "せいしんとういつ" ], "comment": "concentration of mind; mental concentration (on some task)" },
  { "question": "精進潔斎", "answers": [ "しょうじんけっさい" ], "comment": "purifying oneself (religiously) by abstaining from eating meat" },
  { "question": "紅毛碧眼", "answers": [ "こうもうへきがん" ], "comment": "red-haired and blue-eyed (person); a Westerner" },
  { "question": "紅顔可憐", "answers": [ "こうがんかれん" ], "comment": "youthful and endearing; rosy-cheeked and sweet" },
  { "question": "紆余曲折", "answers": [ "うよきょくせつ" ], "comment": "turns and twists; ups and downs; meandering; complications; vicissitudes" },
  { "question": "純一無雑", "answers": [ "じゅんいつむざつ" ], "comment": "pure and unadulterated; pure in heart; simplehearted" },
  { "question": "純情可憐", "answers": [ "じゅんじょうかれん" ], "comment": "pure of heart and pretty" },
  { "question": "純潔無垢", "answers": [ "じゅんけつむく" ] },
  { "question": "純真可憐", "answers": [ "じゅんしんかれん" ], "comment": "pure of heart and beautiful; innocent and beautiful" },
  { "question": "純真無垢", "answers": [ "じゅんしんむく" ], "comment": "pure; purity" },
  { "question": "紛然雑然", "answers": [ "ふんぜんざつぜん" ] },
  { "question": "紫電一閃", "answers": [ "しでんいっせん" ], "comment": "flash of lightning; flash of a sword; brandishing a sword" },
  { "question": "紳士協定", "answers": [ "しんしきょうてい" ], "comment": "gentlemen's agreement" },
  { "question": "紳士淑女", "answers": [ "しんししゅくじょ" ], "comment": "ladies and gentlemen" },
  { "question": "終始一貫", "answers": [ "しゅうしいっかん" ], "comment": "consistently; unchangingly; throughout" },
  { "question": "結縁灌頂", "answers": [ "けちえんかんじょう" ] },
  { "question": "結跏趺坐", "answers": [ "けっかふざ" ], "comment": "sitting with crossed legs; the lotus position" },
  { "question": "絢爛豪華", "answers": [ "けんらんごうか" ], "comment": "luxurious and gorgeous; splendid; dazzling" },
  { "question": "絶体絶命", "answers": [ "ぜったいぜつめい" ], "comment": "desperate situation with no escape; being driven into a corner; being cornered; last extremity" },
  { "question": "綱紀粛正", "answers": [ "こうきしゅくせい" ], "comment": "eliminating corruption among government officials; tightening discipline (among)" },
  { "question": "綾羅錦繍", "answers": [ "りょうらきんしゅう" ] },
  { "question": "緊褌一番", "answers": [ "きんこんいちばん" ], "comment": "gird oneself up" },
  { "question": "総量規制", "answers": [ "そうりょうきせい" ], "comment": "total volume control; regulations on total allowable volumes of pollutants" },
  { "question": "緩急自在", "answers": [ "かんきゅうじざい" ], "comment": "varying the tempo or speed (of something) at will" },
  { "question": "緩歌慢舞", "answers": [ "かんかまんぶ" ] },
  { "question": "縦横無尽", "answers": [ "じゅうおうむじん" ], "comment": "freely; right and left; as one pleases" },
  { "question": "繁文縟礼", "answers": [ "はんぶんじょくれい" ], "comment": "red-tapism" },
  { "question": "罪業消滅", "answers": [ "ざいごうしょうめつ" ] },
  { "question": "罵詈讒謗", "answers": [ "ばりざんぼう" ], "comment": "reviling; vilification; abusive language; lashing somebody using abusive language; speaking abusively of somebody" },
  { "question": "罵詈雑言", "answers": [ "ばりぞうごん" ], "comment": "vilification; vituperation; abusive language" },
  { "question": "羅織虚構", "answers": [ "らしききょこう" ] },
  { "question": "羊頭狗肉", "answers": [ "ようとうくにく" ], "comment": "using a better name to sell inferior goods; crying wine and selling vinegar" },
  { "question": "美人薄命", "answers": [ "びじんはくめい" ], "comment": "beauty and fortune seldom go together; the beautiful die young" },
  { "question": "美辞麗句", "answers": [ "びじれいく" ], "comment": "flowery words; rhetorical flourishes" },
  { "question": "羞花閉月", "answers": [ "しゅうかへいげつ" ], "comment": "the charms of a uniquely beautiful woman; (so beautiful that) flowers are abashed and the moon hides" },
  { "question": "群雄割拠", "answers": [ "ぐんゆうかっきょ" ], "comment": "rivalry of local warlords; a number of powerful (talented, influential) persons standing by themselves in a given field" },
  { "question": "義理一遍", "answers": [ "ぎりいっぺん" ], "comment": "perfunctory; going-through-the-motions-sort of (invitation, gift, etc.)" },
  { "question": "義理人情", "answers": [ "ぎりにんじょう" ], "comment": "duty and humanity; (a sense of) moral obligation and humane feelings" },
  { "question": "羽化登仙", "answers": [ "うかとうせん" ], "comment": "a sense of release (as if one had wings and were riding on air)" },
  { "question": "翠帳紅閨", "answers": [ "すいちょうこうけい" ] },
  { "question": "老少不定", "answers": [ "ろうしょうふじょう" ], "comment": "Death comes to old and young alike; uncertainty of life" },
  { "question": "老幼男女", "answers": [ "ろうようなんにょ" ] },
  { "question": "老若男女", "answers": [ "ろうにゃくなんにょ" ], "comment": "men and women of all ages" },
  { "question": "聖人君子", "answers": [ "せいじんくんし" ], "comment": "person of lofty virtue; man of noble character; perfect person; saint" },
  { "question": "職権濫用", "answers": [ "しょっけんらんよう" ] },
  { "question": "肉食妻帯", "answers": [ "にくじきさいたい" ], "comment": "meat and matrimony (Buddhism); Buddhist priest eating meat dishes and being married" },
  { "question": "肝胆相照", "answers": [ "かんたんそうしょう" ] },
  { "question": "脚下照顧", "answers": [ "きゃっかしょうこ" ], "comment": "look carefully where your own footsteps fall; seek enlightenment by knowing yourself and not by watching others; know thyself" },
  { "question": "脱俗超凡", "answers": [ "だつぞくちょうぼん" ] },
  { "question": "腐敗堕落", "answers": [ "ふはいだらく" ], "comment": "debasement; corruption; degradation" },
  { "question": "腕白小僧", "answers": [ "わんぱくこぞう" ], "comment": "naughty boy; mischievous boy; little rascal; brat" },
  { "question": "臍下丹田", "answers": [ "せいかたんでん" ], "comment": "pit of the stomach" },
  { "question": "臥薪嘗胆", "answers": [ "がしんしょうたん" ], "comment": "going through thick and thin to attain one's objective; enduring unspeakable hardships for the sake of vengeance" },
  { "question": "臨機応変", "answers": [ "りんきおうへん" ], "comment": "adapting oneself to the requirements of the moment; playing it by ear; ad hoc" },
  { "question": "自主独立", "answers": [ "じしゅどくりつ" ] },
  { "question": "自今以後", "answers": [ "じこんいご" ], "comment": "henceforth; henceforward; hereafter" },
  { "question": "自作自演", "answers": [ "じさくじえん" ], "comment": "performing a part in one's own play; playing a musical piece that one has written\ndoing everything by oneself (from preparation to execution)\nput-up job; charade\nsock-puppeting (i.e. pretending to be more than one person on the Internet)" },
  { "question": "自分勝手", "answers": [ "じぶんかって" ], "comment": "selfishness; egotism; egoism; (being) self-centered; without consulting; (doing) as one pleases; one's own free will" },
  { "question": "自問自答", "answers": [ "じもんじとう" ], "comment": "answering one's own question; wondering to oneself; soliloquizing; soliloquising" },
  { "question": "自家撞着", "answers": [ "じかどうちゃく" ], "comment": "self-contradiction" },
  { "question": "自家薬籠", "answers": [ "じかやくろう" ], "comment": "(something that is) available for use at any time; (someone who is) at one's beck and call; (something over which) one has complete mastery" },
  { "question": "自己嫌悪", "answers": [ "じこけんお" ], "comment": "self-hatred; self-abhorrence; self-loathing" },
  { "question": "自己弁護", "answers": [ "じこべんご" ], "comment": "self-justification; excuse" },
  { "question": "自己撞着", "answers": [ "じこどうちゃく" ], "comment": "self-contradiction; self-inconsistency" },
  { "question": "自己暗示", "answers": [ "じこあんじ" ], "comment": "self suggestion; autosuggestion" },
  { "question": "自己欺瞞", "answers": [ "じこぎまん" ], "comment": "self-deception; self-deceit" },
  { "question": "自己満足", "answers": [ "じこまんぞく" ], "comment": "self-satisfaction; (self-)complacency; smugness" },
  { "question": "自己犠牲", "answers": [ "じこぎせい" ], "comment": "self-sacrifice; self-renunciation" },
  { "question": "自己矛盾", "answers": [ "じこむじゅん" ], "comment": "self-contradiction; paradox; antinomy" },
  { "question": "自己陶酔", "answers": [ "じことうすい" ], "comment": "narcissism; self-absorption; self-intoxication" },
  { "question": "自己顕示", "answers": [ "じこけんじ" ], "comment": "making oneself conspicuous; pressing one's own cause" },
  { "question": "自暴自棄", "answers": [ "じぼうじき" ], "comment": "desperation; despair; self-abandonment" },
  { "question": "自業自得", "answers": [ "じごうじとく" ], "comment": "paying for one's mistakes; getting one's just deserts; suffering the consequences (of one's own actions); reap what you sow" },
  { "question": "自殺行為", "answers": [ "じさつこうい" ], "comment": "suicidal act; self-destroying action; suicidal action" },
  { "question": "自浄作用", "answers": [ "じじょうさよう" ], "comment": "autopurificatory activity (in the natural world)" },
  { "question": "自然天然", "answers": [ "しぜんてんねん" ] },
  { "question": "自然淘汰", "answers": [ "しぜんとうた" ], "comment": "natural selection" },
  { "question": "自由奔放", "answers": [ "じゆうほんぽう" ], "comment": "free and uncontrolled; behaving with abandon; freewheeling" },
  { "question": "自由放任", "answers": [ "じゆうほうにん" ], "comment": "laissez-faire; non-intervention" },
  { "question": "自由民権", "answers": [ "じゆうみんけん" ] },
  { "question": "自由自在", "answers": [ "じゆうじざい" ], "comment": "free; unrestricted; (with) complete mastery; completely in control" },
  { "question": "自由闊達", "answers": [ "じゆうかったつ" ], "comment": "free and easy; open and natural; not fastidious" },
  { "question": "自画自賛", "answers": [ "じがじさん" ], "comment": "singing one's own praises; praising one's own wares" },
  { "question": "自給自足", "answers": [ "じきゅうじそく" ], "comment": "self-sufficiency" },
  { "question": "自縄自縛", "answers": [ "じじょうじばく" ], "comment": "being caught in one's own trap" },
  { "question": "至上命令", "answers": [ "しじょうめいれい" ], "comment": "categorical imperative; overriding necessity" },
  { "question": "至大至重", "answers": [ "しだいしちょう" ] },
  { "question": "興亡治乱", "answers": [ "こうぼうちらん" ] },
  { "question": "興味本位", "answers": [ "きょうみほんい" ], "comment": "(just) out of curiosity; (just) in order to satisfy one's curiosity; aimed chiefly at amusing; sensational (e.g. magazine)" },
  { "question": "興味津々", "answers": [ "きょうみしんしん" ], "comment": "very interesting; of absorbing interest; having a keen interest (in); being immensely curious (about)" },
  { "question": "舌先三寸", "answers": [ "したさきさんずん" ], "comment": "eloquence or flattery designed to deceive" },
  { "question": "舳艫千里", "answers": [ "じくろせんり" ], "comment": "a large number of ships sailing in a long chain-like formation" },
  { "question": "良妻賢母", "answers": [ "りょうさいけんぼ" ], "comment": "good wife and wise mother" },
  { "question": "艱難辛苦", "answers": [ "かんなんしんく" ], "comment": "trial and tribulation; hardships; privations; difficulties" },
  { "question": "色即是空", "answers": [ "しきそくぜくう" ], "comment": "form is emptiness; matter is void; all is vanity" },
  { "question": "色相世界", "answers": [ "しきそうせかい" ] },
  { "question": "花街柳巷", "answers": [ "かがいりゅうこう" ] },
  { "question": "花鳥風月", "answers": [ "かちょうふうげつ" ], "comment": "beauties of nature; the traditional themes of natural beauty in Japanese aesthetics\nartistic pursuits involving nature themes" },
  { "question": "苛斂誅求", "answers": [ "かれんちゅうきゅう" ], "comment": "imposing exacting (crushing, oppressive) taxes" },
  { "question": "苦学力行", "answers": [ "くがくりっこう" ], "comment": "strenuous pursuit of learning under difficulties" },
  { "question": "苦心惨憺", "answers": [ "くしんさんたん" ], "comment": "taking great pains" },
  { "question": "苦節十年", "answers": [ "くせつじゅうねん" ] },
  { "question": "英姿颯爽", "answers": [ "えいしさっそう" ], "comment": "cutting a fine (dashing, gallant, noble) figure" },
  { "question": "英雄豪傑", "answers": [ "えいゆうごうけつ" ], "comment": "hero; warrior of matchless valor; heroic character" },
  { "question": "茫然自失", "answers": [ "ぼうぜんじしつ" ], "comment": "stupor; stupefaction; trance; (being) dumbfounded" },
  { "question": "草根木皮", "answers": [ "そうこんぼくひ" ], "comment": "roots of herbs and barks of trees used in Chinese medicine" },
  { "question": "荒唐無稽", "answers": [ "こうとうむけい" ], "comment": "absurdity; nonsense; preposterous" },
  { "question": "荘厳華麗", "answers": [ "そうごんかれい" ], "comment": "majestic and splendid" },
  { "question": "落花啼鳥", "answers": [ "らっかていちょう" ], "comment": "the poetic feeling of a late spring scene (with flowers scattering and birds chirping)" },
  { "question": "落花狼藉", "answers": [ "らっかろうぜき" ], "comment": "running amok (amuck); committing violence on; in utter disorder" },
  { "question": "葷酒山門", "answers": [ "くんしゅさんもん" ] },
  { "question": "蒟蒻問答", "answers": [ "こんにゃくもんどう" ], "comment": "an irrelevant and incoherent dialogue; dialogue at cross purposes; an off-the-beam response" },
  { "question": "蓮華往生", "answers": [ "れんげおうじょう" ] },
  { "question": "薄利多売", "answers": [ "はくりたばい" ], "comment": "small profits and quick returns" },
  { "question": "薄志弱行", "answers": [ "はくしじゃっこう" ], "comment": "infirm of purpose and lacking in decision" },
  { "question": "薬九層倍", "answers": [ "くすりくそうばい" ], "comment": "\"There is a huge markup in medicines.\"" },
  { "question": "虎視眈眈", "answers": [ "こしたんたん" ], "comment": "(watching) vigilantly for an opportunity to prey upon; with an eagle eye" },
  { "question": "虚々実々", "answers": [ "きょきょじつじつ" ], "comment": "full of wiles and tricks; match between persons equal in shrewdness mobilizing all the tricks each can muster; shrewdly avoiding the opponent's strong points and attacking its weaknesses" },
  { "question": "虚実皮膜", "answers": [ "きょじつひまく" ], "comment": "the difference between truth and fiction in art being very subtle; Art abides in a realm that is neither truth nor fiction" },
  { "question": "虚心坦懐", "answers": [ "きょしんたんかい" ], "comment": "with an open and calm mind; with no preconceived notions; without reserve; frank; candid" },
  { "question": "虚静恬淡", "answers": [ "きょせいてんたん" ] },
  { "question": "蛙鳴蝉噪", "answers": [ "あめいせんそう" ], "comment": "annoying noise; fruitless argument; useless controversy" },
  { "question": "蜀犬吠日", "answers": [ "しょくけんはいじつ" ] },
  { "question": "蜃楼海市", "answers": [ "しんろうかいし" ] },
  { "question": "蝸牛角上", "answers": [ "かぎゅうかくじょう" ], "comment": "trifling (fight); (a conflict) between small countries" },
  { "question": "融通無礙", "answers": [ "ゆうずうむげ" ], "comment": "free, unfettered and flexible; versatile; adaptable" },
  { "question": "蟄居閉門", "answers": [ "ちっきょへいもん" ], "comment": "house arrest; being placed in confinement at home" },
  { "question": "蠧紙堆裏", "answers": [ "としたいり" ] },
  { "question": "血脈相承", "answers": [ "けちみゃくそうじょう" ] },
  { "question": "衆人環視", "answers": [ "しゅうじんかんし" ], "comment": "(in) the presence of the whole company; with all eyes filed upon (one)" },
  { "question": "衆口一致", "answers": [ "しゅうこういっち" ], "comment": "speaking with one voice; being unanimous" },
  { "question": "衆生済度", "answers": [ "しゅじょうさいど" ], "comment": "enlightenment of the masses; leading the masses on the path of enlightenment (Buddhism)" },
  { "question": "衆目環視", "answers": [ "しゅうもくかんし" ] },
  { "question": "衆議一決", "answers": [ "しゅうぎいっけつ" ], "comment": "deciding unanimously or by consensus" },
  { "question": "行住坐臥", "answers": [ "ぎょうじゅうざが" ], "comment": "daily life; daily routine; while awake or asleep; at all times; day in, day out; constantly; the four cardinal behaviors - walking, standing, sitting and lying" },
  { "question": "行儀作法", "answers": [ "ぎょうぎさほう" ], "comment": "etiquette; good manners" },
  { "question": "行動半径", "answers": [ "こうどうはんけい" ], "comment": "radius of action; sphere of activity" },
  { "question": "行屎走尿", "answers": [ "こうしそうにょう" ] },
  { "question": "行雲流水", "answers": [ "こううんりゅうすい" ], "comment": "(metaphorically) floating with the tide" },
  { "question": "街談巷説", "answers": [ "がいだんこうせつ" ], "comment": "street gossips and idle rumors" },
  { "question": "衣冠束帯", "answers": [ "いかんそくたい" ], "comment": "full Japanese court dress of traditional fashion" },
  { "question": "衣錦還郷", "answers": [ "いきんかんきょう" ] },
  { "question": "表敬訪問", "answers": [ "ひょうけいほうもん" ], "comment": "courtesy call" },
  { "question": "表裏一体", "answers": [ "ひょうりいったい" ], "comment": "the two views (of an object) referring to the same thing; being inseparable like the two sides of an object; two sides of the same coin" },
  { "question": "被害妄想", "answers": [ "ひがいもうそう" ], "comment": "persecution complex" },
  { "question": "裏面工作", "answers": [ "りめんこうさく" ], "comment": "string-pulling; backstage manoeuvering (maneuvering)" },
  { "question": "複雑多岐", "answers": [ "ふくざつたき" ], "comment": "complex and wide-ranging; labyrinthine" },
  { "question": "複雑多様", "answers": [ "ふくざつたよう" ], "comment": "complex and multifarious" },
  { "question": "複雑怪奇", "answers": [ "ふくざつかいき" ], "comment": "complicated and mysterious" },
  { "question": "襲名披露", "answers": [ "しゅうめいひろう" ], "comment": "announcing the succession to another's stage name" },
  { "question": "西方浄土", "answers": [ "さいほうじょうど" ], "comment": "Western Pure Land (Amitabha's Buddhist paradise)" },
  { "question": "要害堅固", "answers": [ "ようがいけんご" ], "comment": "(a fortress being) impregnable; unassailable" },
  { "question": "見性成仏", "answers": [ "けんしょうじょうぶつ" ] },
  { "question": "見性自覚", "answers": [ "けんしょうじかく" ] },
  { "question": "規制緩和", "answers": [ "きせいかんわ" ], "comment": "deregulation; removal (easing) of (official) restrictions; relaxation of regulations" },
  { "question": "視野狭窄", "answers": [ "しやきょうさく" ], "comment": "narrowing of visual field; narrow-mindedness; lack of vision" },
  { "question": "親類縁者", "answers": [ "しんるいえんじゃ" ], "comment": "one's relatives by blood and marriage (in blood and law); one's kith and kin" },
  { "question": "観測気球", "answers": [ "かんそくききゅう" ], "comment": "weather balloon; sounding balloon\nobservation balloon; espionage balloon; spy balloon\ntrial balloon" },
  { "question": "言文一致", "answers": [ "げんぶんいっち" ], "comment": "unification of the written and spoken forms of a language" },
  { "question": "言行一致", "answers": [ "げんこういっち" ], "comment": "acting up to one's words" },
  { "question": "言語道断", "answers": [ "ごんごどうだん" ], "comment": "outrageous; preposterous; scandalous; inexcusable; absurd; execrable" },
  { "question": "証拠隠滅", "answers": [ "しょうこいんめつ" ], "comment": "destruction of evidence" },
  { "question": "試行錯誤", "answers": [ "しこうさくご" ], "comment": "trial and error" },
  { "question": "誇大妄想", "answers": [ "こだいもうそう" ], "comment": "megalomania" },
  { "question": "誘引開導", "answers": [ "ゆういんかいどう" ] },
  { "question": "誠心誠意", "answers": [ "せいしんせいい" ], "comment": "in all sincerity; with one's whole heart; whole-hearted devotion" },
  { "question": "誠惶誠恐", "answers": [ "せいこうせいきょう" ] },
  { "question": "読書三到", "answers": [ "どくしょさんとう" ], "comment": "using mind, mouth and eyes to understand a book fully" },
  { "question": "読書三昧", "answers": [ "どくしょざんまい" ], "comment": "being absorbed in reading" },
  { "question": "読書尚友", "answers": [ "どくしょしょうゆう" ], "comment": "by reading books you can count the wise philosophers of the past as friends (Mencius)" },
  { "question": "読書百遍", "answers": [ "どくしょひゃっぺん" ], "comment": "Repeated reading (makes the meaning clear); Reading something again and again (will lead one to realize its meaning)" },
  { "question": "誹謗中傷", "answers": [ "ひぼうちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "slander; calumny" },
  { "question": "談論風発", "answers": [ "だんろんふうはつ" ], "comment": "spirited discussion" },
  { "question": "論功行賞", "answers": [ "ろんこうこうしょう" ], "comment": "conferral of honors (honours), according to merits" },
  { "question": "諸事万端", "answers": [ "しょじばんたん" ], "comment": "everything; all things" },
  { "question": "諸子百家", "answers": [ "しょしひゃっか" ], "comment": "Hundred Schools of Thought; general term for the large number of scholars and controversialists, and their respective schools, that flourished during China's Spring and Autumn period and Warring States period" },
  { "question": "諸法無我", "answers": [ "しょほうむが" ], "comment": "idea that all things in the universe lack their own unchangeable substances" },
  { "question": "諸行無常", "answers": [ "しょぎょうむじょう" ], "comment": "the impermanence of worldly things; All worldly things are transitory" },
  { "question": "諸説紛々", "answers": [ "しょせつふんぷん" ], "comment": "divergent opinions abound; opinion is divided; there are many rumors afloat" },
  { "question": "謹厳実直", "answers": [ "きんげんじっちょく" ], "comment": "sober and honest" },
  { "question": "議論百出", "answers": [ "ぎろんひゃくしゅつ" ], "comment": "diverse arguments arising in great numbers" },
  { "question": "豁然大悟", "answers": [ "かつぜんたいご" ], "comment": "suddenly seeing the light; achieving full enlightenment all of a sudden" },
  { "question": "豪放磊落", "answers": [ "ごうほうらいらく" ], "comment": "broadminded" },
  { "question": "豪華絢爛", "answers": [ "ごうかけんらん" ], "comment": "luxurious and gorgeous; magnificent" },
  { "question": "貧富貴賤", "answers": [ "ひんぷきせん" ], "comment": "rich and poor, high and low; people of all ranks" },
  { "question": "責任転嫁", "answers": [ "せきにんてんか" ], "comment": "shift the responsibility (for something) on to (someone); pass the buck" },
  { "question": "貴種流離", "answers": [ "きしゅりゅうり" ] },
  { "question": "貴賤老若", "answers": [ "きせんろうにゃく" ] },
  { "question": "貴顕紳士", "answers": [ "きけんしんし" ], "comment": "gentlemen of (high) eminence; notables; dignitaries" },
  { "question": "賛否両論", "answers": [ "さんぴりょうろん" ], "comment": "arguments for and against; pros and cons; mixed reception; mixed reviews" },
  { "question": "質実剛健", "answers": [ "しつじつごうけん" ], "comment": "unaffected and sincere, with fortitude and vigor (vigour)" },
  { "question": "質朴剛健", "answers": [ "しつぼくごうけん" ] },
  { "question": "質疑応答", "answers": [ "しつぎおうとう" ], "comment": "question and answer session" },
  { "question": "質素倹約", "answers": [ "しっそけんやく" ], "comment": "(practice) simplicity and frugality; scrimping and saving" },
  { "question": "贅沢三昧", "answers": [ "ぜいたくざんまい" ], "comment": "indulging in every possible luxury" },
  { "question": "贔屓偏頗", "answers": [ "ひいきへんぱ" ] },
  { "question": "起承転結", "answers": [ "きしょうてんけつ" ], "comment": "introduction, development, turn and conclusion (quadripartite structure of certain Chinese poetry)\nstory composition and development" },
  { "question": "起死回生", "answers": [ "きしかいせい" ], "comment": "revival from the brink of death; recovering from a hopeless situation; resuscitation; revitalization" },
  { "question": "越権行為", "answers": [ "えっけんこうい" ], "comment": "exceeding one's authority; abusing one's legal authority; ultra vires activities" },
  { "question": "跳梁跋扈", "answers": [ "ちょうりょうばっこ" ], "comment": "being rampant; domination" },
  { "question": "躊躇逡巡", "answers": [ "ちゅうちょしゅんじゅん" ], "comment": "hesitation and vacillation" },
  { "question": "身体髪膚", "answers": [ "しんたいはっぷ" ], "comment": "entire human body; every inch of one's body" },
  { "question": "身心脱落", "answers": [ "しんじんだつらく" ] },
  { "question": "軽佻浮薄", "answers": [ "けいちょうふはく" ], "comment": "frivolous and thoughtless" },
  { "question": "軽便信用", "answers": [ "けいべんしんよう" ] },
  { "question": "軽妙洒脱", "answers": [ "けいみょうしゃだつ" ], "comment": "witty; smart and polished" },
  { "question": "軽挙妄動", "answers": [ "けいきょもうどう" ], "comment": "rash and blind act" },
  { "question": "軽薄才子", "answers": [ "けいはくさいし" ], "comment": "shallow, glib and obsequious person" },
  { "question": "軽薄短小", "answers": [ "けいはくたんしょう" ], "comment": "small and light" },
  { "question": "輪廻転生", "answers": [ "りんねてんしょう" ], "comment": "all things being in flux through the endless circle of birth, death, and rebirth; the circle of transmigration" },
  { "question": "輾転反側", "answers": [ "てんてんはんそく" ], "comment": "tossing and turning in bed; turning over in bed worrying over something" },
  { "question": "轍鮒之急", "answers": [ "てっぷのきゅう" ] },
  { "question": "迅速果敢", "answers": [ "じんそくかかん" ], "comment": "quick and decisive; fast and daring; swift and resolute" },
  { "question": "近所合壁", "answers": [ "きんじょがっぺき" ], "comment": "immediate neighborhood; immediate neighbourhood" },
  { "question": "近郷近在", "answers": [ "きんごうきんざい" ], "comment": "surrounding country; neighboring villages" },
  { "question": "迦陵頻伽", "answers": [ "かりょうびんが" ], "comment": "kalavinka; imaginary bird in paradise that sings sweet notes" },
  { "question": "迷惑千万", "answers": [ "めいわくせんばん" ], "comment": "great nuisance; extremely annoying; quite embarrassing" },
  { "question": "迷惑至極", "answers": [ "めいわくしごく" ], "comment": "great nuisance; extremely annoying; quite embarrassing" },
  { "question": "追善供養", "answers": [ "ついぜんくよう" ], "comment": "memorial service" },
  { "question": "速戦即決", "answers": [ "そくせんそっけつ" ], "comment": "quick battle for a quick victory; blitzkrieg" },
  { "question": "造反有理", "answers": [ "ぞうはんゆうり" ], "comment": "There are no rebels without reasons" },
  { "question": "造次顛沛", "answers": [ "ぞうじてんぱい" ], "comment": "(a) moment" },
  { "question": "連帯責任", "answers": [ "れんたいせきにん" ], "comment": "collective responsibility; joint liability" },
  { "question": "連戦連勝", "answers": [ "れんせんれんしょう" ], "comment": "succession of victories" },
  { "question": "連日連夜", "answers": [ "れんじつれんや" ], "comment": "every day and every night" },
  { "question": "連鎖反応", "answers": [ "れんさはんのう" ], "comment": "chain reaction\nnuclear chain reaction" },
  { "question": "進退両難", "answers": [ "しんたいりょうなん" ], "comment": "being driven to the wall; finding oneself between the devil and the deep blue sea; finding oneself between a rock and a hard place" },
  { "question": "進退去就", "answers": [ "しんたいきょしゅう" ], "comment": "one's course of action; deciding what to do with oneself, whether staying in the present position or leaving it" },
  { "question": "遅疑逡巡", "answers": [ "ちぎしゅんじゅん" ], "comment": "shilly-shally; hesitation; indecision; vacillation" },
  { "question": "遊戯三昧", "answers": [ "ゆげざんまい" ] },
  { "question": "過剰防衛", "answers": [ "かじょうぼうえい" ], "comment": "excessive or unjustifiable self-defense (defence)" },
  { "question": "過大評価", "answers": [ "かだいひょうか" ], "comment": "overestimation; overvaluing" },
  { "question": "過小評価", "answers": [ "かしょうひょうか" ], "comment": "underestimation; undervaluation" },
  { "question": "過当競争", "answers": [ "かとうきょうそう" ], "comment": "excessive competition" },
  { "question": "道心堅固", "answers": [ "どうしんけんご" ], "comment": "being of firm (unshakable) faith and strict practice" },
  { "question": "道聴塗説", "answers": [ "どうちょうとせつ" ], "comment": "shallow-minded mouthing of secondhand information" },
  { "question": "遠慮会釈", "answers": [ "えんりょえしゃく" ], "comment": "reserve and consideration (to others)" },
  { "question": "遠謀深慮", "answers": [ "えんぼうしんりょ" ], "comment": "deep design and forethought; farsighted and deeply-laid plan" },
  { "question": "適材適所", "answers": [ "てきざいてきしょ" ], "comment": "the right person in the right place" },
  { "question": "適者生存", "answers": [ "てきしゃせいぞん" ], "comment": "survival of the fittest" },
  { "question": "遮二無二", "answers": [ "しゃにむに" ], "comment": "desperately; recklessly; rush headlong" },
  { "question": "遺憾千万", "answers": [ "いかんせんばん" ], "comment": "highly regrettable; utterly deplorable" },
  { "question": "酒池肉林", "answers": [ "しゅちにくりん" ], "comment": "sumptuous feast; debauch" },
  { "question": "酔生夢死", "answers": [ "すいせいむし" ], "comment": "idling one's life away" },
  { "question": "酔眼朦朧", "answers": [ "すいがんもうろう" ], "comment": "(with) one's eyes blurred from drinking; with drunken eyes; dazed by wine" },
  { "question": "醇風美俗", "answers": [ "じゅんぷうびぞく" ], "comment": "good morals and manners; genial manners and laudable customs; pristine way of life" },
  { "question": "重厚長大", "answers": [ "じゅうこうちょうだい" ], "comment": "heavy, thick, long, and big (products); massive and heavy (products); heavy (manufacturing)" },
  { "question": "金剛不壊", "answers": [ "こんごうふえ" ], "comment": "firm and solid; sturdy and indestructible; unshakable; adamantine" },
  { "question": "金城鉄壁", "answers": [ "きんじょうてっぺき" ], "comment": "impregnable castle (walls); redoubtable" },
  { "question": "金声玉振", "answers": [ "きんせいぎょくしん" ] },
  { "question": "金殿玉楼", "answers": [ "きんでんぎょくろう" ], "comment": "magnificent palace" },
  { "question": "金波銀波", "answers": [ "きんぱぎんぱ" ], "comment": "sparkling waves; waves sparkling in the moonlight or with the light of the rising (setting) sun" },
  { "question": "金烏玉兎", "answers": [ "きんうぎょくと" ], "comment": "sun and moon" },
  { "question": "金甌無欠", "answers": [ "きんおうむけつ" ], "comment": "flawless; perfect\n(a nation) having never been invaded by outside forces" },
  { "question": "金科玉条", "answers": [ "きんかぎょくじょう" ], "comment": "golden rule (basic principle ensuring success in some activity)" },
  { "question": "金襴緞子", "answers": [ "きんらんどんす" ], "comment": "gold-brocaded satin damask" },
  { "question": "針小棒大", "answers": [ "しんしょうぼうだい" ], "comment": "exaggeration; making a mountain out of a molehill" },
  { "question": "錦上添花", "answers": [ "きんじょうてんか" ], "comment": "adding a crowning touch of beauty (to); giving added luster (to); crowning beauty (honor, grace) with even greater glory" },
  { "question": "鎧袖一触", "answers": [ "がいしゅういっしょく" ], "comment": "(beating someone) hands down; with a single blow" },
  { "question": "鏡花水月", "answers": [ "きょうかすいげつ" ], "comment": "flowers reflected on a mirror and the moon reflected on the water's surface; something that is visible but having no substance; the subtle and profound beauty of poems that cannot be described in words" },
  { "question": "長汀曲浦", "answers": [ "ちょうていきょくほ" ], "comment": "long stretch of winding beach" },
  { "question": "長身痩躯", "answers": [ "ちょうしんそうく" ], "comment": "tall and lean figure" },
  { "question": "門前雀羅", "answers": [ "もんぜんじゃくら" ], "comment": "(a house) looking deserted with few visitors" },
  { "question": "門外不出", "answers": [ "もんがいふしゅつ" ], "comment": "(treasuring something by) never taking (it) off the premises" },
  { "question": "門戸開放", "answers": [ "もんこかいほう" ], "comment": "open door policy" },
  { "question": "閉口頓首", "answers": [ "へいこうとんしゅ" ], "comment": "being at a complete loss as to what to do; being at one's wit's end; being at a loss for an answer" },
  { "question": "閉門蟄居", "answers": [ "へいもんちっきょ" ], "comment": "house arrest; being placed in confinement at home" },
  { "question": "開口一番", "answers": [ "かいこういちばん" ], "comment": "at the very beginning of one's speech; the first thing (one) says after opening the mouth" },
  { "question": "開眼供養", "answers": [ "かいげんくよう" ], "comment": "ceremony to consecrate a newly made Buddhist statue or image by inserting the eyes (thereby investing it with soul)" },
  { "question": "開闢以来", "answers": [ "かいびゃくいらい" ], "comment": "since the creation (of the world); since the dawn of history" },
  { "question": "閑人適意", "answers": [ "かんじんてきい" ] },
  { "question": "閑話休題", "answers": [ "かんわきゅうだい" ], "comment": "Now let's return to the main subject; To return from the digression,.. (in a conversation, speech, or story-telling)" },
  { "question": "間不容髪", "answers": [ "かんふようはつ" ] },
  { "question": "閨秀作家", "answers": [ "けいしゅうさっか" ], "comment": "woman writer" },
  { "question": "閻浮檀金", "answers": [ "えんぶだごん" ] },
  { "question": "阿諛迎合", "answers": [ "あゆげいごう" ], "comment": "ingratiation; sycophancy" },
  { "question": "阿諛追従", "answers": [ "あゆついしょう" ], "comment": "excessive flattery; adulation" },
  { "question": "阿鼻叫喚", "answers": [ "あびきょうかん" ], "comment": "agonizing cries; pandemonium; two of Buddhism's hells" },
  { "question": "阿鼻地獄", "answers": [ "あびじごく" ], "comment": "the Avici hell, the eighth and most painful of the eight hells in Buddhism" },
  { "question": "陣中見舞", "answers": [ "じんちゅうみまい" ], "comment": "visiting soldiers at the front to provide comfort; visit to (gift for) persons hard at work as a sign of support" },
  { "question": "陣頭指揮", "answers": [ "じんとうしき" ], "comment": "taking command of a corps in a battle; command exercised by the leader of a group" },
  { "question": "陰陰滅滅", "answers": [ "いんいんめつめつ" ], "comment": "gloomy" },
  { "question": "陰陽五行", "answers": [ "いんようごぎょう" ], "comment": "the cosmic dual forces (yin and yang) and the five elements (metal, wood, water, fire and earth) in Chinese cosmology" },
  { "question": "陽動作戦", "answers": [ "ようどうさくせん" ], "comment": "diversionary tactics" },
  { "question": "随処任意", "answers": [ "ずいしょにんい" ] },
  { "question": "随処作主", "answers": [ "ずいしょさしゅ" ] },
  { "question": "随縁放曠", "answers": [ "ずいえんほうこう" ] },
  { "question": "隔靴掻痒", "answers": [ "かっかそうよう" ], "comment": "being frustrated because something is not quite as hoped (just as one cannot scratch an itch from outside a shoe); having an itch that one cannot scratch" },
  { "question": "隠忍自重", "answers": [ "いんにんじちょう" ], "comment": "(behaving with) patience and prudence; putting up with something" },
  { "question": "雄材大略", "answers": [ "ゆうざいたいりゃく" ], "comment": "superior talent and strategic wisdom; outstanding abilities and a talent for developing and implementing grand strategies" },
  { "question": "雄蝶雌蝶", "answers": [ "おちょうめちょう" ] },
  { "question": "雅俗折衷", "answers": [ "がぞくせっちゅう" ], "comment": "blending of the classical and colloquial styles" },
  { "question": "雅俗混淆", "answers": [ "がぞくこんこう" ], "comment": "mixture of both culture and vulgarism; mixture of both literary and colloquial (language)" },
  { "question": "集中砲火", "answers": [ "しゅうちゅうほうか" ], "comment": "concentrated fire" },
  { "question": "雑然紛然", "answers": [ "ざつぜんふんぜん" ] },
  { "question": "離合開闔", "answers": [ "りごうかいこう" ] },
  { "question": "離合集散", "answers": [ "りごうしゅうさん" ], "comment": "alliance and rupture" },
  { "question": "難攻不落", "answers": [ "なんこうふらく" ], "comment": "impregnable" },
  { "question": "難行苦行", "answers": [ "なんぎょうくぎょう" ], "comment": "penance; hardship" },
  { "question": "雲合霧集", "answers": [ "うんごうむしゅう" ] },
  { "question": "雲散霧消", "answers": [ "うんさんむしょう" ], "comment": "vanishing like mist" },
  { "question": "雲水行脚", "answers": [ "うんすいあんぎゃ" ], "comment": "itinerant monk being on pilgrimages to many lands" },
  { "question": "雲泥万里", "answers": [ "うんでいばんり" ], "comment": "being poles apart; (there being) all the difference in the world" },
  { "question": "雲烟過眼", "answers": [ "うんえんかがん" ] },
  { "question": "雲蒸竜変", "answers": [ "うんじょうりょうへん" ] },
  { "question": "雲雨巫山", "answers": [ "うんうふざん" ], "comment": "sexual liaison" },
  { "question": "電光影裏", "answers": [ "でんこうえいり" ] },
  { "question": "電光石火", "answers": [ "でんこうせっか" ], "comment": "lightning speed" },
  { "question": "霊台方寸", "answers": [ "れいだいほうすん" ], "comment": "heart; soul" },
  { "question": "霊肉一致", "answers": [ "れいにくいっち" ], "comment": "unity of body and spirit" },
  { "question": "霊魂不滅", "answers": [ "れいこんふめつ" ], "comment": "immortality of the soul" },
  { "question": "霓裳羽衣", "answers": [ "げいしょううい" ] },
  { "question": "青天白日", "answers": [ "せいてんはくじつ" ], "comment": "being cleared of all the charge (brought against one); being found completely innocent" },
  { "question": "青息吐息", "answers": [ "あおいきといき" ], "comment": "deep distress" },
  { "question": "非難囂々", "answers": [ "ひなんごうごう" ], "comment": "enraged outcry; loud protest; being bitterly criticized by others; being loudly denounced by others" },
  { "question": "面壁九年", "answers": [ "めんぺきくねん" ], "comment": "facing a wall for nine years in meditation (by Bodhidharma at Shaolin Temple)" },
  { "question": "面従腹背", "answers": [ "めんじゅうふくはい" ], "comment": "pretending to obey but secretly betraying (someone)" },
  { "question": "面目一新", "answers": [ "めんもくいっしん" ], "comment": "undergoing a complete change in appearance; changing something out of all recognition; a rise in one's reputation" },
  { "question": "面目躍如", "answers": [ "めんもくやくじょ" ], "comment": "with evident joy of having lived up to one's reputation; having an effect of bolstering one's reputation" },
  { "question": "鞭声粛々", "answers": [ "べんせいしゅくしゅく" ] },
  { "question": "韋駄天走", "answers": [ "いだてんばしり" ] },
  { "question": "音信不通", "answers": [ "おんしんふつう" ], "comment": "break in contact; not hearing from; having no communication with" },
  { "question": "順風満帆", "answers": [ "じゅんぷうまんぱん" ], "comment": "smooth sailing" },
  { "question": "頑固一徹", "answers": [ "がんこいってつ" ], "comment": "stubborn; obstinate; sticking to one's views or decisions" },
  { "question": "頑迷固陋", "answers": [ "がんめいころう" ], "comment": "obstinate; stubborn; hard-headed; being incapable of making sound judgments because of a narrow, inflexible and obstinate mentality" },
  { "question": "頭寒足熱", "answers": [ "ずかんそくねつ" ], "comment": "keeping the head cool and feet warm" },
  { "question": "頭脳明晰", "answers": [ "ずのうめいせき" ], "comment": "being clearheaded; having a keen (sharp, brilliant) mind" },
  { "question": "顔面蒼白", "answers": [ "がんめんそうはく" ], "comment": "one's face turning pale (ashen); the color being drained from one's face" },
  { "question": "風俗壊乱", "answers": [ "ふうぞくかいらん" ], "comment": "corruption of public morals; an offense against public morality" },
  { "question": "風光明媚", "answers": [ "ふうこうめいび" ], "comment": "scenic; beautiful; picturesque" },
  { "question": "風声鶴唳", "answers": [ "ふうせいかくれい" ], "comment": "getting frightened even by a slight noise; hearing the enemy in every leaf that rustles; being afraid of one's own shadow" },
  { "question": "風林火山", "answers": [ "ふうりんかざん" ], "comment": "as fast as the wind, as quiet as the forest, as daring as fire, and immovable as the mountain" },
  { "question": "風流三昧", "answers": [ "ふうりゅうざんまい" ], "comment": "taking delight in elegant pursuits; being absorbed in such elegant cultural pursuits as poetry, painting and calligraphy" },
  { "question": "風紀紊乱", "answers": [ "ふうきびんらん" ], "comment": "corrupt public morals" },
  { "question": "飛耳長目", "answers": [ "ひじちょうもく" ], "comment": "sharp eyes and ears used for collecting information far and wide; having the acumen and shrewd discernment gained by widely-collected information; being well-versed on a subject; books which broaden our knowledge" },
  { "question": "飛花落葉", "answers": [ "ひからくよう" ], "comment": "Blossoms fall and leaves scatter; the evanescence (impermanence) of worldly things" },
  { "question": "首尾一貫", "answers": [ "しゅびいっかん" ], "comment": "consistent; unchanging from beginning to end" },
  { "question": "首鼠両端", "answers": [ "しゅそりょうたん" ], "comment": "being unable to make up one's mind; sitting on the fence" },
  { "question": "馬耳東風", "answers": [ "ばじとうふう" ], "comment": "utter indifference; talking to the wall; praying to deaf ears" },
  { "question": "馬鹿丁寧", "answers": [ "ばかていねい" ], "comment": "overly polite; excessively polite; polite to a fault" },
  { "question": "驚天動地", "answers": [ "きょうてんどうち" ], "comment": "astounding; startling; world-shaking; amazing; earth-shattering" },
  { "question": "骨肉相食", "answers": [ "こつにくそうしょく" ], "comment": "blood feud; domestic discord" },
  { "question": "高位高官", "answers": [ "こういこうかん" ], "comment": "(person of) high rank and office (exalted station); persons in high positions" },
  { "question": "高手小手", "answers": [ "たかてこて" ], "comment": "bound hands and arms" },
  { "question": "高歌放吟", "answers": [ "こうかほうぎん" ], "comment": "singing at the top of one's voice" },
  { "question": "高潔無比", "answers": [ "こうけつむひ" ] },
  { "question": "鬼手仏心", "answers": [ "きしゅぶっしん" ] },
  { "question": "魑魅魍魎", "answers": [ "ちみもうりょう" ], "comment": "evil spirits of rivers and mountains" },
  { "question": "鮮血淋漓", "answers": [ "せんけつりんり" ], "comment": "dripping with fresh blood" },
  { "question": "鯨飲馬食", "answers": [ "げいいんばしょく" ], "comment": "drinking like a fish and eat like a horse; eating mountains of food and drink oceans of liquor" },
  { "question": "鳩首凝議", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅぎょうぎ" ], "comment": "put heads together and confer; convene and discuss; go into a huddle (over)" },
  { "question": "鳩首協議", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅきょうぎ" ], "comment": "put heads together and confer; convene and discuss; go into a huddle (over)" },
  { "question": "黄塵万丈", "answers": [ "こうじんばんじょう" ], "comment": "rising cloud of (yellowish) dust" },
  { "question": "黄白青銭", "answers": [ "こうはくせいせん" ] },
  { "question": "黄道吉日", "answers": [ "こうどうきちにち" ], "comment": "very auspicious day for all types of occasions" },
  { "question": "黄金時代", "answers": [ "おうごんじだい" ], "comment": "Golden Age" },
  { "question": "鼓腹撃壌", "answers": [ "こふくげきじょう" ], "comment": "(people) sing the praises (enjoy the blessings) of peace" }
]
}
